<DLPSTEXTCLASS>
   <HEADER>
      <FILEDESC>
         <TITLESTMT>
            <TITLE TYPE="245">Garden and forest [Volume 1, Issue 4]</TITLE>
            <RESPSTMT>
               <RESP>Creation of machine-readable version</RESP>
               <NAME>Preservation Reformatting Division, Library of Congress</NAME>
            </RESPSTMT>
         </TITLESTMT>
         <EXTENT>16 600dpi TIFF G4 page images</EXTENT>
         <PUBLICATIONSTMT>
            <PUBLISHER>Preservation Reformatting Division, Library of Congress</PUBLISHER>
            <PUBPLACE> Washington, D.C.</PUBPLACE>
            <DATE>1999</DATE>
            <IDNO TYPE="DLPS">AJQ0745.0001.004</IDNO>
            <IDNO TYPE="ROOTID">V0000001/I0000004</IDNO>
            <IDNO TYPE="LCCN">05040093</IDNO>
            <AVAILABILITY>
               <P>The University of Michigan Library provides access to these materials for educational and research purposes. These materials are believed to be in the public domain in the United States; however, if you decide to use any of these materials, you are responsible for making your own legal assessment and securing any necessary permission. If you have questions about the collection, please contact digital-collections-help@umich.edu. If you have concerns about the inclusion of an item in this collection, please contact LibraryIT-info@umich.edu.</P>
               <P TYPE="license">No Copyright - United States</P>
            </AVAILABILITY>
         </PUBLICATIONSTMT>
         <SOURCEDESC>
            <BIBLFULL>
               <TITLESTMT>
                  <TITLE TYPE="245">Garden and forest.</TITLE>
                  <TITLE TYPE="OTHER">Garden and forest, a journal of horticulture, landscape art and forestry</TITLE>
               </TITLESTMT>
               <EXTENT>Ten volumes</EXTENT>
               <PUBLICATIONSTMT>
                  <PUBLISHER>Garden and Forest Pub. Co.</PUBLISHER>
                  <PUBPLACE>New York</PUBPLACE>
                  <DATE>March 21, 1888</DATE>
               </PUBLICATIONSTMT>
               <SERIESSTMT>
                  <BIBLSCOPE TYPE="volno">001</BIBLSCOPE>
                  <BIBLSCOPE TYPE="issno">004</BIBLSCOPE>
                  <BIBLSCOPE TYPE="issdate">18880321</BIBLSCOPE>
               </SERIESSTMT>
               <NOTESSTMT>
                  <NOTE TYPE="reformatting">Source Description title and publication information is taken from the LC bibliographic record for this serial.</NOTE>
                  <NOTE>The Biblscope elements in Source Description contains volume number, issue number, and issue date information for the portion of the serial contained in this electronic document.</NOTE>
               </NOTESSTMT>
            </BIBLFULL>
         </SOURCEDESC>
      </FILEDESC>
      <ENCODINGDESC>
         <PROJECTDESC>
            <P>The electronic version of this work was created as part of the preservation digital reformatting of the serial identified in Source Description.</P>
            <P>Header created with script updateheader.xsl on 2023-08-31.</P>
         </PROJECTDESC>
         <EDITORIALDECL N="1">
            <P>This electronic text file was created by Optical Character Recognition (OCR).  No corrections have been made to the OCR-ed text and no editing has been done to the content of the original document.  Encoding has been done through an automated process using the recommendations for Level 1 of the TEI in Libraries Guidelines.  Digital page images are linked to the text file.</P>
         </EDITORIALDECL>
      </ENCODINGDESC>
      <PROFILEDESC>
         <LANGUSAGE ID="eng">
            <LANGUAGE>English</LANGUAGE>
         </LANGUSAGE>
         <TEXTCLASS>
            <KEYWORDS>
               <TERM>Botany -- Periodicals.</TERM>
               <TERM>Gardening -- Periodicals.</TERM>
               <TERM>Gardens -- Periodicals.</TERM>
               <TERM>Forests and forestry -- Periodicals.</TERM>
            </KEYWORDS>
         </TEXTCLASS>
      </PROFILEDESC>
   </HEADER>
   <TEXT N="AJQ0745.0001.004">
      <BODY>
         <DIV1 ID="AJQ0745-V0000001-I0000004">
            
            <P>
               <PB REF="p0001.tif" SEQ="0001" RES="600dpi" FMT="TIFF6.0" FTR="ADV" CNF="811" N=""/>—.,_I___.-I                                                                                                        -a,. I
L i'.~~~ NE ~~'1                   -4 —--:VOL~ I.                                                                                                                                                                     N ~
— c-   -1 -I- Israel i-;uyuyr uuuL~s


~ 1.\      J
aiAR0 FO RF
XAJ. URNAL OF V HORTICULTURE
LAN D SCAP EARTAND FoRESTRY


i  Tyight  MARCD Ai 2,            I I888  M                                        ADE.
PRICE TEN CENTS.]                   Copyright, i888, by THE GARDEN AND FOREST PUBLISHING COMPANY, LIMITED.  [$4.O00 A YEAR, IN ADVANCE.


The Standard Botanies.
GRAY'S BOTANICAL TEXT BOOKS.
At once the most complete and the best Botanical
series Published,
COMPRISING:


ORCHIDS
Palms and Fine Tropical
Plants.
We have the most complete collection of
fine plants in the country.
Descriptions of specimens and a general
catalogue of stock can be had on application
either at
409 5th Avenue, New York City,
OR AT THE
ROSE HILL NURSERIES, NEW ROCHELLE, N. Y.
SIEBRECHT &amp; WADLEY.


Gray's How Plants Grow,
Gray's How Plants Behave,
Gray's Lessons in Botany,
Gray's Field, Forest and Garden
Botany,
Gray's School and Field Botany,
Apgar's Plant Analysis,
Gray's Manual of Botany,
Gray's Lessons and Manual,
Gray's Structural Botany,


Goodale's Physiological Botany,
Gray's Structural and Systematic
Botany,
Coulter's Manual of the Rocky
Mountains,
The same, Tourist's Edition,
Gray and Coulter's Manual of
Western Botany,
Gray's Synoptical Flora —The Gamopetalie,
Chapman's Flora of Southern U. S.


"'These books combine'literary grace and substantial instruction in
singularly happy union."
Send for our new descriptive pamphlet of Gray's Botanies,
containing PORTRAIT AND BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH of the
Author.
Books for Introduction or examination furnished on very
favorable terms.
IVISON, BLAKEMAN &amp; CO.,
753-758  Broadway, New  York,
DA N D
149 Wabash Avenue, Chicago.


WESTERN N. C. ORNAMENTAL SHRUBS AND TREES.
Descriptive Price List sent on application. Detailed
description of the new Rhododendron Vaseyi, with each
List. Azalea arborescens is one of our specialties.
Correspondence solicited.
KELSEY BROS., HIGHLANDS NURSERY, Highlands, N. C.
FARQUHARS' SEEDS
BOSTON
Cultivators who want the CHOICEST Flowers and
Vegetables, please write for our new Catalogue. It describes many rare and choice specialties of great merit,
offered only by us, at very moderate prices. Our business is among the best horticulturists in America, and
the quality of our seeds is unsurpassed. Catalogues
(in elegant steel-blue and gold cover, with fine color
work) FREE TO ALL.
THE FOLLOWING ARE SPECIALLY FINE. POSTAGE FREE.
Primula obconica, pkt. 40C.; Turner's Carnations,
pkt. 50oc.; Cinerarla hybrida, new large - flowering,
pkt. 5cc.; Cyclamen, new large flowering, mixed colors,
pkt. 5oc.;  Gloxinia, new large upright flowering,
pkt. 50c.; Pansy, Farquhar's Show flowers, mixed, pkt.
of Ioo seeds, 25c.; Sweet Peas, Kent-grown, superior
to all, mixed colors, ounce, Ioc., pound, $1.oo; Nastiirtiums, Running, Kent-grown, mixed, extra fine, ounce,,5c., pound, $I.75.
PINK POND LILY ROOTS (Nymphea odorata
roseaJ. New, hardy; the finest hardy aquatic. Strong
roots, $2.50 each, postage paid.
R. &amp; J. FARQUHAR &amp; CO.,
Importers, Growers and Dealers in
Reliable Seeds, Bulbs, Etc.,
16 &amp; 19 So. Market St.,Boston, Mass.


H. W. S. CLEVELAND,
LANDSCAPE GARDENER,
221 SECOND AVE. S.,
MINNEAPOLIS, MINN.


CHARLES ELIOT,
LTN DS C;7:E= CG:F1 DDE N D:F2,
9 PARK ST., BOSTON.
Designs for laying out Public and Private Grounds,
Gardens, Parks and Building-Estates.
Consultations on the care and improvement of Country
and Seaside places.
Working-Drawings, Planting-Plans &amp; Superintendence.


-I,'4..   ~ I 
-I- I",


I   I
I
s
I
-  I
I
I
I
1
ii
I 
i
11
i
1.


i
i.
I,
I
I~
i'l
sL
I
t,


i


C~k~YiMU~ IULLY         -   -    -.- --  --  -,~-      LI-14~ULLI-LI —-                                -  -   -   -— l   -   -  -   -  -   \  -   r  -y —                   -  ~-    — rrr-             -*P0      C   "-        -  - r-        -       la-'   -




A



</P>
            <P>
               <PB REF="p0002.tif" SEQ="0002" RES="600dpi" FMT="TIFF6.0" FTR="ADV" CNF="834" N="ii"/>Garden and Forest.


MEEH"ANS' NURSERIES
__w   _S     RARE TREES A SPECIALTY. HAD 750    B
KINDS AT THE CENTENNIAL EXHIBITION.
TOMERS, WHO GET THE BEST STOCK AT
LOWEST FIGURES. THE CHEAPEST WAY
TO BUY. ILLUSTRATED CATALOGUE OF
TREES, FRUITS, SEEDS, &amp;C., SENT OF    For lawn and cemetery planting. These can
6 CENTS IN STAMPS.           now be furnished in great variety, from our
THOMAS MEEHAN &amp;SON,  extensive collection, at reduced prices.
GERMANTOWN, PHILA., PA.    We have now on hand a large supply of the
following rare Beeches, all of which have been
H ARDce 11           R  PLAd   S.. recently transplanted, and are in consequence
IRISES, both Japanese and German, PURPLE-LEAVED BEECH.
in  large  variety;  PHLOXES, all the               From 6 to IO feet high; elegant specibest sorts. TRITOMAS, PERENNIAL                   mens. All were grafted from the beautiful
best  sr. ROICAS, LILIESNIAML       II"Rivers' variety," so justly celebrated for
POPPIES, VERONICAS, LILIES, CAM-                  the intense blood-red color of its foliage.
PANULAS, and all the new as well as
old kinds in great variety.                   WEEPING  BEECH.
Our collection has long been ranked               From 6 to IO feet high, suitable for imas the first of its kind, and as we deal          mediate effect, and well supplied with
in Hardy  Plants exclusively, we can              decidedly pendulous branches.
offer better Plants for less money than
it is possible to procure elsewhere.   CRESTED  and  FERN-LEAVED
Send  Stamp for our Catalogue.                  BEECHES.
We  offer a superb  stock of these,
Lock Drawer E.  Passaic, N. J.        averaging in height from 5 or 6 to IO feet,
all well rooted and nicely furnished.
OLD t~    11STRAWBERRY, a New Berry of very In EVERG REEN S
~   i.-liJ  fine quality, now offered for the firs,  We have now in stock a large supply of
time. Also, JEWELL, JESSIE, BELMONT, and other
varieties Address, P. M. AUGUR &amp; SONS, Originatorst  American, Siberian and Golden Arbor
MIDDLEFIELD, CONN.                                Vitzes, Balsam Firs, Hemlocks and Norway Spruce; good, young, healthy plants,
F  0   R  E  s  T    T  R  E  E  s.             especially desirable for screens and hedges.
4r    Catalpa speciosa,   In SHRUBBERY
J'  ~       j'White Ash, European      Our assortment is very complete, em-,,,,,' Larch, Pines, Spruces,  bracing many rare and elegant species.
Arbor Vitas, etc., etc.  Our immense stock of some kinds enables
Forest and Evergreen
if I - Forest an-;bd Evergreen  us to accept orders at very low rates.
Seeds,
Picea pungens, and
Pseudotsuga Douglasii HOOPE
of Colorado. Two of
the finest and hardiest Maple   Avenue    Nurseries
Conifers in cultivation.
R. DOUGLAS &amp; SONS, -  -  Waukegan, III.               WEST  CHESTER, PA.


YOU are about to write for a catalogue. No doubt you
want the best-the truest descriptions, the clearest
notes on plant culture, plainest type and most beautiful
illustrations. We have put forth every effort to make ours
such. Those who have seen it, say it is. It tells many
reasons why you can buy SEEDS and Plants-so many
of which are grown on the Western prairies-better and
cheaper at CHICAGO than you can elsewhere. Then
why not do so? Our Chicago Parks Flowers and Plants;
our Market Vegetables, and our Gardening Implements
make up a book that
TELLS THE WHOLE STORY,
and is a work of art which will please you.  Send 15
cents and receive the catalogue and a paper of the above
seeds free.
J. C. VAUGHAN,    CHICAGON
88 STATE STREET,


[MIARCH 21, I888.


HE BEST
Accident
Insurance
is that provided
by
THE UNITED
STATES
MUTUAL
ACCIDENT
ASSOCIATION
320, 322 &amp; 324
Broadway,
New York.
Charles B. Peet,
President.
James R. Pitcher,
Secretary and Gen'l Manager.


E GIVE to every purchaser the privilege
of RETURNING THE MACHINE within
W    thirty days if not ABSOLUTELY SATISFACTORY in every respect.
REMINGTON
Standard Typewriter.
SEND FOR ILLUSTRATED PAMPHLET.
WYCKOFF, SEAMANS &amp; BENEDICT,
339 Broadway, New York.


Linen Papers and Typewriter Supplies of all kinds.


ii


I
i
I
I
1
4
4
i
4
i



</P>
            <P>
               <PB REF="p0003.tif" SEQ="0003" RES="600dpi" FMT="TIFF6.0" FTR="TPG" CNF="871" N="37"/>GARDEN AND FOREST.
PUBLISHED WEEKLY BY
THE GARDEN AND FOREST PUBLISHING CO.
[ LIMITED.]
OFFICE: TRIBUNE BUILDING, NEW YORK.
Conducted by........... Professor C. S. SARGENT.


ENTERED AS SECOND-CLASS MATTER AT THE POST OFFICE AT NEW YORK, N. Y.
NEW YORK, WEDNESDAY, MARCH 2I, I888.


TABLE OF CONTENTS.
PAGE.
EDITORIAL ARTICLES:-Needs of American Pomology.-The Proposed Speedroad in Central Park.-Ghent Azaleas............................... 37
Landscape Gardening, IV.................Mrs. Schuyler Van Rensselaer.  38
Horticulture in Florida..................................A. H. Curtiss. 39
A Disease of Certain Japanese Shrubs............Professor Wolcott Gibbs. 40
FOREIGN CORRESPONDENCE:-The Kew  Arboretum............ Geo. Nicholson.  40
Floral Notes from  London................ i......  iiam  Goldring.  41
PLANT  NOTES:-Hardy Begonias.-Grevillea  Thelemanniana.-Allium  Neapolitanum.-Ornithogalum  Arabicum.-Akebia  quinata.-Strelitzia
angusta............................................................. 4
Wayside Beauty (with illustration)....................................... 42
Iris bracteata (with illustration).....................Sereno Watson  43
Sweet Peas.............................................A. H. Fewkes.  43
Polyanthus Narcissus..................................................44
Annuals for Cut Flowers................................... Wm. Falconer  45
Hepatica and Blood-root.........................Professor W. W. Bailey.  45
The Propagation of Magnolias..........................ackson Dawson.  45
Rules for Planting Wind-breaks................... Professor L. H. Bailey. 46
THE FOREST:
The Forests of Vancouver Island...........Professor yohn Macoun. 46
Propagation of Conifers from Seeds in the Open Air.....Robert Douglas.  47
RECENT PUBLICATIONS:-Review of Forest Administration in British India for
the year x885-6...................................................... 48
RECEN'r PLANT PORTRAITS...............................................   48
PERIODICAL LITERATURE:-Art Amateur.-Cassell's Family Magazine.-Longman's Magazine.-McMillan's Magazine.............................  48
FLOWER MARKET...........................................................  48
Illustrations:-A Country Road...........................................  42
Iris  bracteata.........43.............................................
Chinese Narcissus Grown in Water.................................   44
Needs of American Pomology.


i. Statistics should be gathered to determine the relative
profitableness of fruit-growing in different localities.  It is
now demonstrated that most parts of the'country are
adapted to fruit-growing of some kind. For home use and
local markets, the cultivation of fruits of all kinds should be
encouraged over as wide an area as possible. But there
are some fruits whose productiveness varies greatly in
different sections, and nothing is gained to the country or
the individual by encouraging their cultivation on a large
scale in unfavorable situations.
To obtain more definite information than we now have
regarding the best situations for the various fruits, statistics
of the yield in different parts of the country for a series of
years are needed. These statistics might be thrown in
graphic form upon a map, showing at a glance the areas
over which a given fruit, say the peach, yields a fair crop
every year, other areas in which there has been a good crop
on an average once in three or five years, and still others in
which the trees rarely reach a bearing age. Something
of this kind could be done by horticultural societies. Let
statistics be taken at a few  typical points, such as at
South Haven, in Michigan, representing the "fruit belt,"
and Jackson or Ann Arbor, representing the interior of the
State. Similar points for comparison might be chosen in
Pennsylvania, Delaware and other States. Information so
collected would help to show to what extent the fruits are
grown in the locations to which they are best adapted.
2. It is time for an advance in the matter of classifying
varieties. The labors of Warder and the Downings need to
be enlarged and extended. A reliable manual for the
identification of fruits is greatly needed. Some promising
systematic work on the cultural varieties of fruits and vegetables has been done, but before satisfactory progress can
be made in this direction there must be good herbarium
collections of such plants. Cultural varieties are almost
unknown in the herbariums of botanists, but collections of


37


such varieties are a necessity for their proper study. The
distinctions between cultural varieties are so much less than
those between the natural species and varieties, that for their
proper study, it will more often be necessary to refer to the
living plants; but the varieties which require to be studied
together cannot always be obtained at one time in the
living state, nor can they be maintained in the growing
condition at the proper stage long enough for that purpose.
3. The systematic improvement of fruits needs more
attention.  The more promising methods of obtaining
better varieties are:
(a.) Selecting the best from among the varieties accidentally produced. In this way nearly all our varieties in
cultivation have been obtained. A sharp eye, quick judgment and a taste for trying new sorts are what is needed
for this purpose.
(b.) Planting seeds of the best known varieties.  Most
of these are of short standing; many are of the nature of
sports; but the tendency of like to produce like exists to
some degree in all of them and renders it probable that the
best varieties of the future will come from the best of those
we have.
(c.) Better cultivation and changes of soil and climate.
Favorable conditions are an important factor in the production of improved varieties. The finest fruits, as a rule,
have arisen in the localities best adapted to their growth.
Unfavorable conditions may, however, be useful for testing
varieties before they are brought into general cultivation,
and a long continued breeding up in a given locality
may be necessary in order to produce varieties able to
withstand extreme conditions, as of cold or drought.
(d.) The improvement of our wild fruits.  These, by
reason of the long period of their development in the
country, are likely to be best adapted to its climate. Our
cultivated raspberries and blackberries indicate what may
be done in a short time with native species.
(e.) The importation of promising foreign fruits. Most
of our cultivated plants are importations. This is not
because our native resources of this kind are meagre,
but mainly because there has been a longer time abroad
in which to develop improved varieties. Further importation of foreign fruits is especially needed, of kinds not
native to this country, and from regions having similar
climatic conditions.
The Proposed Speed-road in Central Park.
CERTAIN gentlemen of this city who own fast horses
have been aiming for years to get possession of a
portion of Central Park and convert it into a road, broad,
straight and level, whereon their trotters may be speeded,
without any annoyance from vulgar animals or their
drivers.  Some attempts at public meetings have been
made in order to invest the project with the dignity of a
popular movement; but these have all proved melancholy
failures. Nevertheless a bill has been prepared, and is now
before the proper legislative committee in Albany, to authorize the construction of such a road, one hundred feet
wide, and to compel the people to pay for the work of desolating their pleasure ground. The gentlemen who have
tried to organize these meetings for the spoliation of the
Park and who are throwing the weight of their influence in
favor of this bill are described as "opulent citizens."  It
does not follow that a citizen is public-spirited because he
is opulent, but, as a matter of fact, some of the abettors of
this scheme have a certain civic pride and can generally be
counted on for the unselfish support of any measure looking towards the city's welfare. It would not be surprising
that a man whose loftiest ambition is to be known as the


owner and driver of the fleetest trotting horse in the world
should be willing to turn the grassy stretches of the Park
into a bladeless desert to furnish a track for the exercise
and display of this noble animal. The pity of it is that
one intelligent and fair-minded man can be found who
does not understand that the condemnation of any portion


MARCH 21, I888.]


Garden and Forest.



</P>
            <P>
               <PB REF="p0004.tif" SEQ="0004" RES="600dpi" FMT="TIFF6.0" FTR="UNSPEC" CNF="891" N="38"/>38


Garden and Forest.


of the Park to such a use would mean its utter ruin; or
who, if he does comprehend this, entertains the belief that
the plain people who would be permitted to sit on a bench
by the road-side and see him drive by, would, in this way,
drink in a delight which would more than counterbalance
any loss or pain, caused by a destruction of the pastoral
beauty of the Park.
Now, the only reason which justifies the setting apart of
so large an area for a park in the heart of a city like New
York is, that on ground less spacious, it would be impossible to secure any broad, reposeful examples of rural
scenery. As it is, the limits of Central Park are all too
scanty. The triumph of its designers' skill lies in the fact
that a narrow strip of land, broken and folded into ridges
of rock, has been turned into a series of tree-bordered
meadows, each one giving glimpses of what promise to
be still fairer and more quiet fields beyond. It is this
pastoral scenery, and its restful, healing influence upon
the minds of those who are worn and wearied with the
strained and artificial conditions of city life, which gives
the Park its value. This is the fundamental purpose of the
Park;'and the roads and paths and bridges are only of
value as they help the visitor to obtain the refreshment
offered by its quiet prospects.
The gentlemen who are able to possess fast horses, do
not stand in need of this refreshment as much as some of
their less favored fellows. Their winters are passed in the
sunshine of the South and their summers in villas at Lenox
or cottages by the sea. But to the poor and the children
of the poor the Park offers the only glimpse of greensward
that greets their eyes from one year's end to the other.  It
seems a cruelty to destroy these pictures of peace that a
wise forethought has prepared for them simply to enable a
few "opulent citizens" to enjoy their chosen pastime for a
few weeks in the Spring and Autumn.  And this is especially true, because the Park and its scenery add nothing to
the enjoyment of these horsemen, who find in the driving
itself its own exceeding great reward.  Some of these gentlemen have famous picture galleries, and all right-minded
persons would sympathize with their horror and distress
if some vandal hand should cut out a strip from the border
of one of their favorite landscapes.  But the living picture
is just as truly a work of art as the painted one, and the
cutting away of this broad stretch of verdure and substituting for it something entirely incongruous with its motive
and purpose would be an outrage quite as brutal.
It is discouraging that elementary principles like these
need to be stated now after the Park itself has been for
thirty years pleading its own excuse for being. But there
are men who do not hesitate, when their minds are filled
with the clamors of a controlling passion, to argue in favor
of some encroachment upon the Park that "it was made
to use and not to look at."  The notion at the bottom of
this is, that the only legitimate use to which land in a city
can be put is to be built upon or trampled over, or in some
way "improved" or occupied.  Even a Park Commissioner
who had a scheme to fill up one of the fairest vales of Central Park with cheap carpentry once justified his purpose
by calling the spot "a piece of unimproved land." So long
as it is not recognized as a principle of action that beauty
may be in itself of the highest use; so long as it is not understood, that from the most practical, common sense
view, the primary " use" of a pleasure ground like Central
Park is "to be looked at," just so long every urban park
in the country is threatened with destruction.
There is no need therefore to state here the special objections to this speed-road.  There are difficulties in law
to be urged by those who have the right to enter the Park
and cross this track.  There are enormous difficulties


in the way of its construction. There are difficulties which
would destroy its value as a track for fast driving even if
it could be built. But these special objections might not
hold against the next threat of invasion; and one encroachment will certainly be followed by another, for there are a
hundred classes of people-each with a claim upon the


[MARCH 21, i888.


city's pleasure ground as valid as that of the fast driversand every one will feel encouraged to pre-empt a quarter
section here or there for the special business or pleasure in
which its members are chiefly interested.
What is needed most is intelligent opinion as to the primary uses and purposes of well-planned and planted parks.
Their value as breathing spaces, as aids to purify the air,
as places for exercise, is constantly and properly urged;
but it is only when their higher function, their healthful
influence upon the mind, is universally appreciated, that
the foundation is laid for the strongest resistance against
attacks upon their integrity.
Ghent Azaleas.
HENT Azaleas, as they are generally known in horticultural literature, are a race of garden hybrids
produced in the first place by crossing Azalea Ponh'ca with
different American species, especially A. calendulacea, A.
vzscosa and A. nudzJfora, and then improved by selecting
the best varieties raised from the seed of these hybrids.
They are, perhaps, when in flower, the most beautiful of
all our hardy shrubs. They are equally beautiful when
massed in great beds or when grown singly.  Their brilliant, deliciously fragrant flowers range in color from crimson and pink, through orange and yellow to almost white.
No plants bloom  more freely and few  last longer in
bloom. These Azaleas flourish in good garden soil, but
like the evergreen Rhododendrons, they cannot bear lime,
and the region where they can be grown in the United
States therefore is not very large.  Although the plants
are all perfectly hardy, the blossom buds of some varieties are killed in severe winters and some grow less vigorously than others.
The following varieties, selected for a large collection,
are hardy, vigorous and free blooming, their flower buds
never suffering in the most severe winters: Henry Waterer,
Belle Merville, Heureuse Surprise, Madame Baumann,
Fama, Gloria MIundi, Astreans, Grand Monarque, Pallas,
Beaute Celeste, Prince Henri de Pays Bas.
Hardly inferior in beauty to any of the varieties of
this garden race is our native Azalea calendulacea, and
one of the great sights of this continent for the lover of
flowers is the slopes of the Southern Allegheny Mountains when they are blazing in June with the great flamecolored masses of this splendid plant.
But these hybrid Azaleas can, perhaps, be still further
improved, or their blooming period, at least, greatly extended, by mingling with them  the blood of Azalea arborescens, a very late-blooming, hardy species, with white, fragrant flowers, from  the Carolina Mountains, and of the
Californian A. occzdetalzhs, another late blooming species.
Their further improvement offers an inviting field of experiment.
These plants are spoken of here as Azaleas; in reality
they are all Rhododendrons, for Azalea only differs from
Rhododendron in its deciduous leaves, a view now accepted by botanists, but, in speaking of them from a cultural
point of view, much confusion will be saved by retaining
Azalea, the name by which they are universally known in
gardens.
Landscape Gardening.-IV.
T has been said that though the landscape gardener
works with Nature's own materials and processes, he
does not lack those opportunities for self-expression, which


alone make art a possibility. His task is to produce beautiful compositions-beautiful pictures. Nature supplies him
with his factors-always gives him vitality, light, atmosphere, beautiful colors and charming details, and often
lovely or imposing forms in the configuration of the soil;
and she will see to the perfect finishing of his design. But
his design is the main thing and must be of his ownT conceiving.



</P>
            <P>
               <PB REF="p0005.tif" SEQ="0005" RES="600dpi" FMT="TIFF6.0" FTR="UNSPEC" CNF="889" N="39"/>Garden a


It is easy to see that this is true when it is a question of
formal, "architectural" design in gardening.  But it is
just as true when it is a question of the most "natural"
landscape work. Nature seldom  shows the artist a large
composition which he can wish to reproduce; and if by
chance she does, it is impossible for him to reproduce it.
Practical difficulties hedge him narrowly in, and appropriateness-which in every art is a prime considerationcontrols his efforts more imperiously than those of most
other artists.
If the painter finds a natural scene which, without alteration, would please him upon canvas, he can paint it as
he finds it and take his picture where he will. If Nature
will not help, she will not hinder him, nor will appropriateness forbid his savage, or his arctic, or his tropical landscape to hang upon a wall in Paris or New York. But the
gardener cannot reproduce such a landscape if he would,
and appropriateness would forbid him if he could. He
cannot even reproduce a scene nearer home, the appropriateness of which, in general effect and in details of vegetation, might be entire. His aim is never purely ideal;
he can never think simply of beauty or even of appropriateness in the abstract.  He may practice with abstract
problems on paper, but with each piece of his actual work
Nature says to him: Here in this spot I have drawn a
rough outline, which it is for you to make into a picture.
In many other spots I have shown you scattered beauties
of a thousand kinds. It is for you to decide which of them
you can bring into that picture, and for you to discover
how they may be fused into a whole "which shall look as
beautiful, as right, as though I had created it myself."
Thus we see that appropriateness must be the touchstone as regards not only general effects, but particular
features. The memory may be stored with endless beauties that Nature has revealed -with innumerable "bits" of
composition, with pregnant ideas for foregrounds, backgrounds, middle distances and "effects" of every sort, and
with exhaustless materials in the way of trees and shrubs
and flowers. But not one can be used without bringing
the mind to bear upon the questions: Will it, theoretically,
be appropriate in this part of the world?  Can I, theoretically, introduce it into a creation of this special sort? And
will practical, local considerations permit me to introduce
it, if I find it theoretically appropriate? Indeed, the true
process of landscape creation is more synthetical, more
imaginative than this. The true artist will not go about
with a store of ready-made features and effects in his mind
and strive to fit them into the composition of the moment
as best he may.  He will conceive his general idea in
deference to the local prescriptions of Nature; develop his
general scheme as artistic fitness may seem to counsel;
discover the special features and details which are needed
to perfect it (considering which Nature will permit among
those that he might desire); and then, half unconsciously
perhaps, search for memories of natural results which may
teach him how to achieve his own. In educating himself
he will have tried less to remember in a definite way those
particular results of Nature which he may have seen than
to understand how Nature goes to work to produce beautiful results-to permeate himself with her spirit, to comprehend her aims, to learn what she means by variety in
unity, by harmonious contrasts, by appropriateness of
feature and detail, by beauty of line and color, by distinctness of expression-in a word, by composition. He will
have tried to train his memory of general rather than his
memory of particular truths, and chiefly to.purify his taste
and to stimulate his imagination; —for he will have known
that, while in some ways he is'Nature's favorite pupil, in
other ways she treats him  more parsimoniously than the


rest. She gives him a superabundance of models by the
study of which he may make himself an artist; but when
as an artist he is actually at work she will never give him
one which, part by part, can guide him in his effort. When,
we read of painters we marvel most not at the modern''realist" working\ inch by inch from the living form, but at


nd  Forest.                                            39
Michael Angelo on his lonely scaffold, filling his Sistine
ceiling with forms as true as Nature's, and far more powerful and sup.erb-no guides at hand but his memory of the
very different forms he had studied from the life and his
own creative thought. Yet something very like this is
what the landscape gardener must do every time he takes
a piece of work in hand. Certainly not each of his tasks is
as difficult as a Sistine ceiling, but each, whether small or
large, whether hard or easy, must be approached in the
same way that this ceiling was approached. Is his work
not, therefore, pre-eminently artistic work? Does it not
give him full chance to express himself since it calls so imperatively at every step for the exercise of the imagination,
and since the best memory in the world can only give him
general, and not special, counsels?
M. G. Van Rensselaer.
Horticulture in Florida.'THE cold wave which swept over Florida in January, I886,
marked the beginning of a new epoch in her development.  Before that time orange culture had been made to
advertise the State so extensively that it had come to be regarded as the all-important industry, and thousands even of
her inhabitants looked upon it as the only one that could be
carried on with profit here.  Therefore this killing frost was
regarded as an unmitigated disaster. True, the groves within
the orange belt proper were not seriously damaged, but a
cloud was cast on the title of the orange to public confidence, and the result has been that for the past two years
Florida has suffered partial eclipse.  But there are strong indications that the obscuration will not last much longer.
The orange fever will hardly.be revived and it is far from
desirable that it should be.  While it continued we suffered
all the evils of a one-crop system. Besides, it diverted immigration from that large portion of the State where oranges
cannot be grown with profit, but where people can more readily make a living by mixed agriculture.  The great freeze,
therefore, did some good in checking rash investment and
reckless planting and turning people's attention to more substantial branches of rural industry.
Besides the orange no fruits had obtained much favor in
Florida before I886, except a few of a still less hardy nature. For
a few years the Lemon had been planted largely in southern
Florida and the fruit was shipped in considerable quantity.
Being less perishable, it promised soon to rival the orange in
public favor. The Lime succeeded finely in the same region,
as did the Grape fruit, Citron and Shaddock, but they were
but little grown except for ornament and home use.
In the orange belt the Guava (Psidium j5omiferum in varieties,
and to a less extent P. Cattleianurm) had come to be regarded
as a standard fruit, and deservedly so, for there is scarcely
another that can be put to a greater variety of uses, or
used more months in the year. In I885 it was plentiful in the
Jacksonville market, but it could hardly be shipped fresh out
of the State. These with Bananas (planted mainly for ornament), Figs, improved native Plums (Prunus angustifolia), the
Scuppernong Grape, and more rarely some inferior Peaches
and Pears, the Japan Persimmon, the Loquat (Eriobolrya) the
Mulberry, Pomegranate, and a few varieties of improved
Grapes, comprised the minor fruits of the Citrus belt.
The Cocoanut and Pineapple, formerly confined to the
southern keys, were coming into notice as fruits adapted to
the latitude of Lake Okeechobee, and the latter fruit had succeeded well on the eastern coast as far north as Cape Canaveral.
The Mango (Mfanfgifera Indica) and Avocado Pear (Persea
gratissimna) had fruited bountifully as far north as Tampa.
These and other sub-tropical fruits were planted still further
north, and there was a growing disposition to put them to the
severest test in a climate subject to a lower range of temperature than they could by nature endure.
Such was the situation when the memorable cold wave


swept over us, driving the mercury down to a lower mark by
four degrees than had been known since I835. To make
matters worse this cold wave was of twice the usual duration,
which is two days.  All Citrus fruits that had not been
gathered, except in the southernmost counties and on the
Indian River, were frozen. The Orange groves which had
been the pride of Florida, were stripped of their foliage and
remained bear and dreary during the remainder of the winter.
Weak trees were seriously damaged, as were Lemon and Lime
trees, while Guavas and the whole list of sub-tropical fruits
were killed to the ground.


MARCH 21, I888.]



</P>
            <P>
               <PB REF="p0006.tif" SEQ="0006" RES="600dpi" FMT="TIFF6.0" FTR="UNSPEC" CNF="884" N="40"/>40


Garden and Forest.


Native trees of sub-tropical species, such as the Black Mangrove (Avicennia hitida) and the Rubber Tree (Ficus aurea),
some of them fifty years old, were killed, proving the exceptional severity of the weather. North of latitude 30~ on the Atlantic side of the peninsula, and 29~ on the Gulf side, neglected
and unprotected Orange groves were badly damaged, while
some even on the northern border of the State were scarcely
injured, except by loss of foliage, which began to put out again
in March.
This event, occurring at the beginning of the tourist season,
and when southern California had just become accessible to
tourists, proved disastrous to Florida in its immediate effects;
yet looking toward the ultimate welfare of the State, it must
result beneficially. The Orange has shown itself to be much
hardier than was supposed. Attention has been turned from
sub-tropical fruits, and in seeking for substitutes many hardy
fruits have been brought into notice, which will add greatly to
the people's comforts and sources of income. Faith in the
one-crop system has given place to desire for greater variety.
The people have been led to inquire and experiment, and by
this means have come to know that the orange belt, as well as
the cotton belt of the State, is adapted to a great variety of
profitable and attractive industries. That some progress has
been made in the way of fruit-growing will be shown in another letter.
Jacksonville, Fla.                     A. H. Czurtiss.
A  Disease of Certain Japanese Shrubs.
APANESE shrubs form, as every horticulturalist knows,
conspicuous ornaments of modern gardens, and are in
many cases to be regarded as indispensable. All that concerns
them is, therefore, of interest, and details of the experience
even of a single amateur may not be without interest. In my
own garden at Newport, R. I., the exposure is towards the east,
and the distance from the sea-beach about one-eighth of a
mile. The soil is light, but fairly good, with underlying clay.
The prevailing wind during the greater part of the year is from
the south-west. The average winter temperature is higher
than 2o0 F. Lower temperatures are not very frequent, but
temperatures as low as o0, or even lower, do occur, though
not for more than one or two days at a time, and not more
frequently than once or twice in the course of a winter. The
spring is always very cold and late-a fact which was noted by
Bishop Berkeley during his residence on the island in I728-34.
For a number of years I have observed that spring arrives at
Cambridge, Mass., nearly a fortnight earlier than at this place.
Warm days in April are very often followed by very cold
nights. The cool and delightful summer is followed by a long,
very cool autumn, not favorable to the perfect ripening of
bulbs.
I have for some years cultivated Japanese and Chinese
shrubs with an especial predilection, and have noted the
following curious fact in regard to a number belonging to different natural orders: Some time in July or August the tips
of the new shoots begin to look sickly, then wither, turn brown
and finally die down to the root, leaving a number of other
branches in a healthy condition. This I have observed in
Rosa rugosa, Cercis 7acionica, Acer polymor5khumn and varieties,
Exochorda grandzifora and Stagliylea Bumalda.  I have not
been able to detect the presence of any insect, and have found
no remedy, except the heroic one of cutting out all affected
branches. As a rule the root remains sound and sends up new
shoots during the ensuing spring. Exochorda grandifiora has
suffered most and for several successive seasons. The disease
showed itself for the first time in the summler of I886 in an old
and very large group of Rosa rugosa, and again during the
past summer in some much younger plants. Cercis yajionica
is not hardy here, but is killed to the ground every spring. The
new shoots invariably begin to die down in July.  Viburnum.plicatum is not affected, and I have not observed the disease
in  Amfielossis Veitchii or in Cercidizhhyllum   afionicum,
Rhodotypus Kerrioides, Hydrang~ea paniculata grandiflora,
Actinidia pfolygama, A/kebia quinata or in Eleagnus longiz5es,
which last summer bore a prodigious crop of an agreeable
acid fruit. I have already stated that on this island very warm


days in April are often followed by very cold nights. Two
years since beautiful hedges of Lonicera Halleana were killed,
root and branch, by alternate heat and cold in April, while
Lonicera yabonica and Lonicera brachypoda aureo-reticulata
also suffered severely, although in a less degree. It may prove
that the disease which I have observed is also due to alternations of heat and cold, and perhaps that it is analogous to the
frozen sap-blight which affects the pear.
Newport, R. I.     W                      Wolcott Gibbs.


[MARCH  21, I888.


Foreign  Correspondence.
The Kew Arboretum.
r HE living collection of trees and shrubs in the open
air at Kew is by far the most extensive of any in
Europe. It is intended in these notes to give an account
of the most remarkable specimens of this famous arboretum, but it seems first of all desirable to give a sketch of
its history, so that some idea can be formed of the way in
which, from a small beginning, Kew has attained its
present importance. About the middle of the seventeenth
century Kew-and this short, familiar name I shall use to
designate the Botanic Gardens and Arboretum-belonged
to a gentleman named R. Bennett, whose daughter and
heiress married Lord Capel, who died Lord Deputy of Ireland in I696. Lord Capel in reality was the first to begin
the formation of a botanical collection by importing rare
trees and shrubs from France. It was not, however, until
a long lease of Kew had been obtained from the Capel
family by the Prince of Wales that much was done in altering and laying out the grounds. The mother of George
III., Augusta, the Princess Dowager of Wales, some years
after the death of her husband, resided at Kew, and decided
to make a botanic garden. In this work, which she took
great pleasure in personally superintending, she received
much assistance from the Earl of Bute, a liberal patron of
men of genius, both in literature and in the arts, but probably the most unpopular English minister of modern times.
It may be worth mentioning here that Lord Bute's favorite
study was botany, and that he published a quarto work in
nine volumes, entitled " Botanical Tables," a whim which
it is said cost him ~Io, ooo; only twelve copies were
printed.
In I759 William Aiton, a pupil of the celebrated Philip
Miller, the friend and contemporary of Linneus, was
placed in charge of the gardens. Aiton laid out and
planted as an Arboretum, according to the Linnaean system, a piece of ground about five acres in extent. Many
of the finest foreign trees were contributed in 1763 from
his garden at Whitton by Archibald, Duke of Argyle, surnamed by Horace Walpole, the Tree-monger. The following testimonial to the ability and character of this nobleman
is given by Peter Collinson (the friend and contemporary
of Linnaeus), a famous old gardener, who was the first to
introduce to cultivation in Britain, through his friends Bartram, Catesby, and others, a host of North American trees,
shrubs and plants: "The Duke of Argyle, on the s5th of
" April, I76I, died as he sat in his chair, my honored friend
" and great patron of all planters, aged 79, a very hearty
"man of that age. In the year I723-4 he took in a part of
"Hounslow Heath, to add to a little farm, and began plant" ing by raising all sorts of trees and shrubs from seeds from
" our northern colonies and all other parts of the world; he
" had the largest collection in England, and happily lived to
"see to what a surprising maturity they had arrived in thirty" seven or thirty-eight years. Great was his benevolence,
" for he gave to every one to encourage planting, and raised''plants on purpose to oblige the curious at this seat of his,
" called Whitton. He had a fine collection of rare birds and
"beasts; he was a great chemist, natural philosopher, me" chanic, astronomer and mathematician.  He tas a won" derfully amiable man, plain in his dress, without pride or''vain ostentation; his library was scarcely to be equaled.
" He was 41 years old when he began to sow seeds for his
"plantations." Several of the trees presented to Kew by the
Duke of Argyle are still flourishing in their original positions, and a detailed account of some of them will be given
by and by.


It would be a waste of time to give minute details respecting Kew and its fortunes between the periods mentioned above and I84I, although there is not the slightest
intention to underrate the services of the second Aiton, nor
of his able colleague, Mr. John Smith, A.L.S., who is still
hale and hearty, and takes a lively interest in all matters



</P>
            <P>
               <PB REF="p0007.tif" SEQ="0007" RES="600dpi" FMT="TIFF6.0" FTR="UNSPEC" CNF="889" N="41"/>Garden an


horticultural.* The next step of most importance was the
appointment of Sir W. J. Hooker in 1841- The greater portion of what is now. the Aboretum was then called the
Pleasure Grounds, and was simply nothing more or less
than a game preserve. The new Director lost no time in
calling the attention of the government to the cramped accommodation for the hardy ligneous collections, and urged
the formation of a National Arboretum. A plan was drawn
out by Nesfield, one of the foremost landscape gardeners
of his time, and the lines laid down by him  have in a
broad sense been followed. When Her Majesty relinquished the grounds- in I840 the "Board of Green Cloth"
ceased to control the destinies of Kew, and it was placed underH. M. CommissionersofWoodsandForests. In 1843 permission was granted to utilize a. piece of ground measuring forty-eight acres as a pinetum; of this plot the noble
palm house may now be said to form the centre. A considerable number of fine Conifers still exist of those planted
at that time. Not until I85o were the Pleasure Groundsmore than I78 acres in extent-diverted from their use as
a game preserve and devoted to their present purpose.
For some time before the appointment of Sir W. J. Hooker,
Kew had languished for want of efficient support, but ever
since that event the establishment has progressed by leaps
and bounds. After the death of Sir W. J. Hooker, his son,
Sir J. D. Hooker, reigned in his stead, and no one in the
scientific world is unaware of the services rendered to horticulture and botany by the late director.  The appointment of Mr. W. T. Thistleton Dyer to his present post is a
comparatively recent occurrence, but the works carried out
by him sufficiently prove that the establishment will develop still further and will maintain its position at the head
of the botanic gardens of the world.
Kew, February, x888.              George Nicholson.
Floral Notes from London.
A new race of hybrid Begonias has been originated by the
Messrs. Veitch, of Chelsea, which promises to become of considertble value for winter flowering.  The foundation of this
race is the new Begonia Socotrana, which was discovered and
introduced a few years ago by Professor Balfour when exploring the little known island of Socotra in the Gulf of Aden.
This species is distinct from other cultivated Begonias, having
shield shaped or round leaves, and flowers of symmetrical outline about one and one-half inches across and of a bright rosepink.  It flowers naturally in winter, and so it occurred to the
Messrs. Veitch that a good result could be obtained by intercrossing the Socotra Begonia with some high colored varieties
of the South American species, especially with those having
distinctly tuberous roots and which bloom in summer. The first
attempt resulted in the production of a pretty variety showing
intermediate characters between the parents. It had more
rounded leaves than its parent, B. insignis, while its flowers,
though smaller than those of B. Socotrana, were more highly
colored. It was named Autumn Rose because it began to
flower in autumn and continued nearly throughout the winter.
The next cross of B. Socotrana was with a tuberous variety,
and the pretty hybrid named John Heal resulted. It is a dwarf
compact plant, producing flowers very freely, and continuing
in bloom through the winter. The flowers are of a bright
cherry-crimson.  A third variety is named Adonis, which has
much larger flowers than the preceding two, more regular in
form and of a pleasing rose-pink.  The most recent hybrid is
called Winter Gem, a cross between B. Socotrana and a highly
colored tuberous variety. It has large, bold leaves, almost as
round as those of the Socotra Begonia, and large flowers of good
shape of a brighlt rosy-crimson borne well above the foliage.
Messrs. Veitch have a large number of seedlings yet to flower,
and judging by the rate of advancement in the few hitherto
produced, some good things may be expected.
The White Bornean Jasmine is one of the loveliest and


most fragrant plants one can grow for a continuous supply
of cut bloom during winter. At least, it is so here, and, no
doubt, the plant would behave as well in America. It is rather
a new plant, introduced by Messrs. Veitch a few years ago


* Since the above letter was written the veteran ex-curator of the
Royal Botanic Gardens has passed away at the age of ninety years.
-ED.


td  Forest.                                           4I
from Borneo.  It has a tendency to climb, its shoots being
slender and rambling. It flowers abundantly; every twig bears
a cluster of blossoms. It delights in a warm andmoist house,
and if in a light position will produce a continuous crop of
bloom for several weeks.
The Double Chinese Primula, Eva Fish, is not a new variety,
having been put in commerce years ago by Messrs. Henderson, but rarely, if ever, has it been seen in such perfection as
at an exhibition of the Royal Horticultural Society at a late winter meeting, when it was honored'with a certificate.  It is distinct from all the others in point of color, which is, a sort of
plum-purple. The flowers are very large, perfectly double,
being, in fact, like compact rosettes, and are borne in great
trusses, rising well above the luxuriant foliage.  There is no
other double Primula of a similar color to compare with this
one, and it will probably become even more popular than
heretofore. Each flower of the double Primula makes a neat
buttonhole bouquet and they are much used for this purpose.
Wm. Goidrilng.
Plant Notes.
Hardy Begonias.- -Mr. Pringle's note concerning the re-discovery of Begonia gracilis in Northern Mexico, reminds me to
ask why the old hardy Begonia Evansiana (discolor) is so
much neglected. I once had a bed of these plants in northern
Maryland, which occupied the same spot for eight or ten
years. The bulbs were occasionally lifted and reset, as they
became too thick in the bed, but had little other attention,
being treated as a little group in the shade of trees in an outof-the-way place. The plants came through a temperature of
I8~ below zero in I88o, without any covering. My practice was
to plant early Tulips among them, in the fall, to make a bit of early
color, and by the time the Begonia leaves appeared above ground
the Tulips were ready to be lifted. In autumn the bed was a
mass of rosy bloom, until frost cut the flowers down. I have
never seen it planted elsewhere, and it is now hardly known
except in old green-houses, where it sometimes becomes
almost a weed from the dropping of the bulblets from the axils
of the leaves. It is far more reliable as a bedder than any
Begonia I ever used.
Crozet, Va.                              W. F. Massey.
Grevillea Thelemanniana.-This elegant little Proteaceous
plant is one of the prettiest of the genus, and a native of
Australia.  It attains a height of three to five feet, and has
slender, drooping branches, terminated by pendulous racemes
of bright red flowers tipped with yellow, their beauty being enhanced by the delicate pinnate leaves. Although a scarce
plant it is a comparatively easy one to grow, and will do well in
company with Azaleas. It should be potted in a compost of
equal parts of peat and loam with a good sprinkling of sand;
care should be taken not to give it too much pot-room. During
the winter months-which is the time the flowers generally appear-the plants should be kept comparatively moist at the root,
but the atmosphere of the house should be dry, and a temperature from 450 to 550 maintained. The Proteaceae are not so
popular as they should be, probably on account of the extra
attention the plants require during the hot days of summer,
when neglect of watering may result in their death. A good
plan in summer is to plunge the pots to their level, out of
doors where water is handy.  This species is easily increased
by cuttings of half-mnatured shoots inserted in sand in a cool
house.                                      F. Goldring.
Allium Neapolitanum is the prettiest white flowering species
of the genus, a native of southern Europe, barely hardy here,
but well fitted for pot culture. We had it in capital bloom in
February in a cool green-house. The bulbs are roundish, very
small and silvery gray, the foliage is flat and moderately broad,
and the flowers quite pretty, white and loosely arranged in full
umbels terminating a scape some fifteen inches long. The
plants set and ripen seed freely and bysowing this seed a fresh
stock of the plants can be readily secured.


Ornithogalum Arabicum.-Dry bulbs of this plant potted last
October and then grown along in a cool green-house are nowin
bloom. The flowers are large, white with black centres, showy
and in flat-headed racemes terminating scapes, some eighteen
to twenty-four inches long. The foliage is long, flat and slender,
but I cut it into about half its length and in this way secure a
tidy form. This species and 0. lacteum, from South Africa, are
the best for pot culture, and both are easily grown.   W: F.


MARCH 21, I888.]



</P>
            <P>
               <PB REF="p0008.tif" SEQ="0008" RES="600dpi" FMT="TIFF6.0" FTR="UNSPEC" CNF="889" N="42"/>Garden and Forest.


Akebia quinata.-In Philadelphia we can grow, with a little
protection, many of the southern vines, such as the Carolina
Jasmine, Berchemia volubilis, Bignonia capreolata and Decumaria
barbara, a privilege denied to many but a few degrees north of
us. But after all we could hardly spare the useful and pretty
Akebia quinata. Its trifoliate leaves, though apparently so
tender, when young, are sturdy enough for any weather, and
the plant itself defies our most severe winters.  Its rapid
growth, and its early plum-colored flowers with their delicious
fragrance make it altogether desirable. When planted where
thick, yet not dense, shade is required, no vine is more effective. It rarely produces fruit here, yet on several occasions
specimens of the fruit have been exhibited at our Horticultural
Society. One of the best ways to propagate the Akebia is to
take half-ripened wood in midsummer, cut into lengths of
from one to two eyes each, and insert them in pans of
sand and water.                        yosepih Meehan.


[MARCH 21, I888.


bright purple. The flowers are so placed as to resemble a flying bird, and justify the popular name of "Bird of Paradise
Plant."                                 W. A. HMranda.
Wayside Beauty.
IN these days there is no lack of advice to plant trees by every
roadside, and Village Improvement Societies are furnishing good examples of neatly kept highways. But many of our
country roads are already bordered with trees and shrubs and
climbing vines of Nature's own planting, and it is quite as important to preserve the wild beauty of this spontaneous growth
as it is to provide for the more formal and stately rows of Elms
and Maples which are planted on Arbor days. The illustration
below gives a glimpse of a New England by-road which,
fortunately, has escaped the axe and brush-hook of the enterprising path-master. Many officials in charge of our highways


A Country Road.


Strelitzia augusta.-Most gardeners are familiar with the
Strelitzia Reginoa, generally cultivated and flowered in our
green-houses, but the plant named above is rarely seen and
still more rarely in flower. It does not bloom until it is from
fifteen to twenty-five years of age, but afterwards it keeps pushing up its curious spathes of flowers which last long in perfection. Aside from the showy flowers which are produced
nearly the whole year round, its stately form and large leaves
make it conspicuous. Those only can enjoy its possession,
however, who have large green-houses, for the plant grows
from 15 to 20 or more feet in height. Its culture is simple. It
flourishes best if planted out in the green-house in a good, rich
compost of loam, sand and leaf-mould, and in this way it will
take an unlimited amount of water. It can be grown from
seed as well as from offshoots which are produced from the
base of the plant. It is related to the Banana which it resembles in appearance and structure. The stem is marked with
irregular rings where the leaves have separated. The leaves
are large, oblong-lanceolate and slightly arching. The stout
scape branches out into three or four spathes resembling
small canoes, from which the flowers are produced in succession. The three nearly equal sepals are eight inches long and
pure white, while the two halbert-shaped petals are smaller and


appreciate the value of trees when planted in straight rows
and at equal distances, but a group of Cockspur Thorn, or
Sassafras, or Black Haw, or a thicket of Sumach, or Hazel-nut,
is too often looked upon as a disfigurement and a proof that
the overseer is neglecting his duty to keep the roadside neat
and clean.  Miles on miles of wayside beauty are sacrificed
every year to this mania for " trimming up," but the trees and
shrubs spring up again to clothe the desert made by man. In
smooth and level regions a strip of greensward bordering the
wheel-way and running under the open fences into adjoining
fields is always pleasing, and it cannot be too neatly kept. But
in all hilly and stony regions east of the Alleghanies, no lovelier road-border can be conceived of than the native trees and
shrubs which flourish wherever they are left to themselves.
Every one recalls some narrow lane or by-way, with fern-embroidered thickets on either hand, where the June Berry and
Wild Plum and Witch-Hazel blossom above the Roses and
Honeysuckles and Red-root; where the Wild Grape covers
the nakedness of the stone walls and the Bitter-sweet swings
from the branches of the trees overhead; where wild flowers
can be found in bloom any day between April and November;
where the brown thrush sings and the rabbit makes her home.
Indeed, it would be difficult to name a spot where there is


42



</P>
            <P>
               <PB REF="p0009.tif" SEQ="0009" RES="600dpi" FMT="TIFF6.0" FTR="UNSPEC" CNF="854" N="43"/>MARCH 21, i888.]


Garden and Forest.


43


more of natural beauty and melody and fragrance than a country roadside against which the hand of improvement has not
been lifted.
Iris bracteata.*
AMONG the peculiar species of the genus Iris which are
~. found upon the Pacific slope of North America, the one
here figured is one of the more notable and interesting. From
near the extremity of its slender rootstock it sends up a flowering stem which is covered by loose sheathing and overlapping
bracts, purplish, and scarcely differing from  the bracts which
subtend the flowers.  The flowers are usually large, either
nearly pure yellow or the recurved sepals (or "falls," as they
are sometimes called), veined with bluish purple.  The tube
of the flower is very short and funnel-shaped, and the sepals,
as in all Western species, are without beard or crest.  The
-     \         \\'  \ "  petals are narrow and erect, and the narrow styles are much
prolonged beyond the anthers. The leaves that arise from the
x\ X'X''\~t//~ "D 1rootstock are solitary, at first sheathed at base by several thin,
equitant bracts which appear to soon dry and wither. The
leaf itself is linear and taller than the stem, thick and leathery,
and persistent to the second or third year.  When dry, the
V'\                           margins become revolute as a consequence of a dissimilarity
in the two surfaces. The ordinary equitant leaf of Iris is as if
it were folded longitudinally upon itself, so that the two surfaces are identical in character.  Here, while one side is
smooth, close and bright green, as usual, the other is lighter
colored, with a very thin cuticle crowded with stomata, making it, of course, much more hygrometric.
This species was found by Mr. Thomas Howell, of Arthur,
Oregon, in 1884, in the mountains of Josephine County, very
l/!/,  near the southern boundary of that State, flowering in the lat-:| f X/1/1  \!XE\1  \   ter part of April and in May.  In I887 he again visited the
1\\ \\ X!,locality and secured roots, from  which it is hoped that the
plant mnay be introduced into cultivation.  In its characters it
is'most nearly allied to I. Dougicasiana, which is common in
11 H                    I / \'. \XX'a the Coast Ranges of California from  Del Norte to Alameda
County. That species is much more leafy, and the usually
pale lilac flowers have a much longer and narrower perianthI \  l',l  \\tube. The accompanying figure is from a drawing by Mr. C.
i  iiI IE. Faxon.                                             S. W/
Sweet Peas.
t! \   li i Aft'-I   O~UT  of thirty-one named varieties of Sweet Peas, planted,~vZ  ~                x J////   f,1j  for trial last year, I found but nineteen really distinct
kinds. Cardinal was practically identical with Invincible Scar-. lXi  /l llet; so was Princess Louise, with The Queen; Queen of the
Isles, with Invincible Red Striped; Violet Queen and Grand
Blue, with Light Blue and Purple; Purple Striped, with Black
and White; Captain Clark and Lotty Eckford, with Blue Edged.
Princess Beatrice is one of the most beautiful, with large,
clear rose-pink flowers. Miss Ethel and Isa Eckford are nearly
identical with it, but somewhat inferior. Adonis is similar,
but darker, a deep carmine-pink. The Queen has a standard
of deep rose, tinged with purple, and darker wings-a finely111,9 lI: jil/f/   11 l   l~ll formed flower, a trifle dull in color. Vesuvius is quite distinct,
with standard of rosy-crimson, lighter at the edges, spotted and
I':1\\/  1  ij 1  1  Z   veined toward the centre with darker color, and wings of rosy
purple, spotted like the standard.
Of scarlets, Invincible Carmine is the best, being an improve
11111  i t 1   01ment on Invincible Scarlet, with broad standards, the rich color
deepened in the wings and heavily shading the keel. Duchess
of Edinburgh is similar, but with standard of lighter color and
a white keel. Scarlet Striped has a white ground shaded and
striped with scarlet, while Invincible Red Striped has scarlet
ground, striped and blotched with white.
No pink and white variety is as good as Painted Lady, though
f\l55 ri1               Crown Princess of Prussia is beautiful, but of lighter color.
Captain Clark has a white standard shaded with rose and
veined with dark lines, and white wings tinged with rose and
edged with purple. Fairy Queen is nearly pure white, with a
few delicate, crimson veins in the centre of the standard. Butterfly is white, faintly edged and shaded with blue.
{\l.iflllW  1W                Among the blues, Bronze Prince is an improvement on In

digo King, having better formed standards, the purplish crimQQ Q~~k&lt; ~son  distinctly  tinged  with  bronze.   Violet' Queen  shows a
* I. BRACTEATA, Watson, Proc. Amer. Acad., xx. 375.  Rootstock slender; leaves
solitary, rigid, much exceeding the stem (one -or two feet long by half an inch
broad or less), striate, one side green and the other glaucous, revolute on drying;
stem angled, covered with imbricated sheathing bracts two to four inches long;
bracts of the spathe approximate, thin-foliaceous, two or three inches long, twoFig. 8.-Iris bracteata.                            flowered; perianth-tube short, funnel-form; sepals oblong-oblanceolate, two or
three inches long, recurved, yellow, usually veined with bluish purple; petals
erect, oblanceolate, somewhat shorter; anthers longer than the filaments; styles
long-crested; capsules exserted, ovate-oblong, an inch long.



</P>
            <P>
               <PB REF="p0010.tif" SEQ="0010" RES="600dpi" FMT="TIFF6.0" FTR="UNSPEC" CNF="892" N="44"/>Garden and Forest.


[MARCH 21, I888.


Fig. 9.-Chinese Narcissus growh in water.


reddish violet tinge in the wings, and Imperial Blue shows
more blue than others of this class. Princess of Wales and
Purple Striped are the best of the dark-striped varieties, the
one blue and white and the other purplish crimson and
white.
The most useful of all for cut flowers is the old Pure White.
Unfortunately it is a rather poor grower, and therefore the announcement last year that an improved variety of Pure White
had been shown at an English exhibition was gratifying to all
who take a special interest in these beautiful and fragrant flowers. Other new varieties at English exhibitions, spoken of as
distinct and promising, are Primrose, Mauve Queen, Splendor
and Apple Blossom, whose names give some indication of their
color.                                    A. H. Fewkes.
"It cannot be too often repeated that care should be taken
not to willfully destroy the native features of the scene. Many
gardeners assume that before beginning their plantings they
must dig up everything that Nature has made to grow; whereas
experience proves that they would accomplish their end much
sooner and better if they should try to second Nature by making slight changes here and careful additions there."
From C. C. L. Hirschfeld's Theorie der Gartenkunst, Leipzig,
1777.


Polyanthus Narcissus.
THE ancient Chinese custom of growing the Polyanthus Narcissus in water to bloom at the advent of their New Year
was brought to San Francisco by emigrants from the Celestial
Empire more than a quarter of a century ago. The fashion has
now reached the east, and it is not very uncommon to see this
plant growing in this way in the houses of Boston and its suburbs. The cultivation of the Narcissus in water is very simple.
The bulb is placed in a shallow bowl or deep plate, about six
weeks before it is wanted in flower, and, according to the
Chinese habit, is surrounded with small bright-colored stones
probably to prevent it from tipping in the plate; this is filled
with water and should be placed in the dark until root-growth
is made. When the roots appear the plant should be placed
in a sunny window and will require no further care beyond. a
daily addition of fresh water.
The variety of Narcissus brought by the Chinese to this
country and from here introduced into England, is known as
the Grand Emperor. The Chinese bulbs are exceedingly vigorous. They are nearly double the size of those of other varieties of this species of Narcissus, and when grown in water sometimes throw up leaves and flower-stems three feet in height.
The Chinese Narcissus is an interesting and attractive house
plant. Our illustration above is from a photograph of a plant
grown near Boston.


44



</P>
            <P>
               <PB REF="p0011.tif" SEQ="0011" RES="600dpi" FMT="TIFF6.0" FTR="UNSPEC" CNF="879" N="45"/>Annuals for Cut Flowers.
A  NNUALS suitable for cut flowers are also the mostsuitable
for garden decoration. They should be:ready growers
and free bloomers, and have bright, showy or fragrant flowers, with stiff stems, and they should last well when cut. And
we should grow enough to enable us to have large clusters of
a kind rather than a few blooms only of each. While Gaillardias and French Marigolds bloom all summer long, Asters and
Mignonette last but a few weeks, and Poppiesnot many days.
To have annuals, therefore, in good condition all summer long,
we must make two or more sowings of many kinds. I make
repeated sowings of Asters, Mignonette, Phlox, Candytuft and
the like, not only to succeed themselves, but also to succeed
Hollyhocks, Canterbury Bells, Veronicas and other plants that
bloom before midsummer, and are then cut over. And as
many of the spring-sown annuals, Zinnias and African Marigolds, for instance, become disheveled before they have quite
finished blooming, I never hesitate to clear them away and replace with fresh plants. This necessitates keeping up a reserve stock, which I always do, and in this way have as fine
Zinnias, Eldorado Marigolds, Scabious, Salvias and some
other annuals, until frost overtakes them, in October, as in July.
In order to have good flowers we must grow them in good
ground.
We have a great variety of uses for cut flowers. Cannas,
African Marigolds, miniature Sunflowers, large Poppies and
Zinnias appear to good advantage in large bunches in roomy
halls, and if cut with long leafy stems so much the better. For
parlor and dining-room tables and brackets we should use the
most beautiful flowers, and such as are pleasantly, but not
strongly, fragrant. A mixture of many kinds of flowers together in one vase should be avoided.
In addition to the annuals that are most desirable for cut
flowers we have a large assortment well fitted for garden
decoration, and from which, too, we may cull many a bouquet;
for instance, Sweet Alyssum, Schizanthus, Clarkia,. Browallia,
Mimulus, Godetia, Cornflowers and the like.
The following are all worth sowing for cut flowers:
China As'ters.-Truffaut's Improved Pwonia Perfection, Victoria, Crown and Reid's Quilled are capital. By sowing in'
March, the end of April and the first of June we can have
Asters from July till October. Crimson, rose and white are the
most desirable.
C'andytuft.-Rose and white are the most desirable colors.
Sweet-scented, Spiral and Dwarf Hybrid White are the best
summer varieties; and Gibraltarica is preferred for wintering
over in frames.
Cannas.-If sown in March in the green-house, and planted'
out in May, these should bloom in September.
Single Dahlias.-These grow readily from seed and seedlings four to five months old bloom freely.
Drummond Phlox.-The grandi fora section is best. Sow
now or in April and again early in June.
Gaillardias.-The annuals, as G.4icta, and its double variety,
Lorenzia and G. amblyodon, bloom abundantly from June till
October, but with age the plants get sprawly, hence the necessity of a successional sowing in May. The perennial G.
aristata and its grandi.fora and maxima forms also bloom
well as annuals.
Larkspur.-Although showy, the annuals are not good
enough for cut flowers, but some of the perennial species,
notably Delphhinium g-randiflorum, bright and beautiful, are
very free flowering when treated as annuals.
AMlarig-olds.-Of the English, Meteor is good in early summer and fall; and of African, the Eldorado strain is unsurpassed. Among French Marigolds tile double striped are
best, still many prefer the brown or mahogany color.
Mignonette.-Miles' Spiral is one of the best. Sow early and
in good ground.
Nasturtiums.-These are desirable on account of their
brightness and lasting qualities. Lobb's varieties are better
than either the common tall or dwarf annuals.
Pansies.-The Trimardeau gives us the largest flowers. Sow
in June for fall flowers, and in August for spring use.
Petunias.-Bunches of double Petunias are quite pretty, and
last well. They grow freely from seed, and bloom when
about three months old, but we cannot reasonably expect


more than twenty-five per cent. to come double.
Po~iiies, especially the double sorts, last in good condition
for two or three days when cut before they are fully open.
Sow broadcast about the end of March or first of April.
Scarlet Salvia.-This can be treated as an annual sown in
February in-doors and in May out-doors. The flowers last
only for a day or two.


45


Scabious.-The large-flowered section and the very dark
plum-purple and white varieties are' best, and they bloom all
summer long.
Stocks.-The large-flowered ten-week Stocks, scarlet and
white, are the best, and it is better to make repeated sowings
than to depend upon the Intermediate Stocks for a supply in
fall.
Sweet Peas.-Sow in rich soil just as soon as the frost is out
of the ground. The first sowings are always good; sometimes
the successional sowings will not bloom at all.
Sunflowers.-The "New Miniature" (which is Ielianthus
cucumerifolius pure and simple) is best. The flowers are
small, bright golden yellow, with dark centres, and have none
of the coarse appearance peculiar to the ordinary Sunflowers
seen in gardens.
Verbenas.-The Mammoth strain is best. Sow early, say in
February or March, and plant out in May in rich, moist
ground. Verbenas. will not thrive in hot, dry, poor land.
Vincas.-The pure white variety, and the white, with red eye,
are best. Sow early and plant out in late May' in a warm,
sunny exposure.
Zinnias.-The new one, grandizfora plenissima, gives the
largest flowers, but the dwarf, double white, yellow and scarlet
give the mIost satisfactory results. Never buy mixed seed, as
it not only contains much poor stuff, but many " washy " colors.
Win. Falconer.
Hepatica and Blood-root.
AMONG the flowers which vie with each other in being the
first to welcome April, the Trailing Arbutus is, at the
East, as early as any. Even- now, however, in early March,
the blue-eyed Hepatica is opening in our garden, to which we
transplanted it from the' woods. It always succeeds in cultivation; but to see it in' its beauty one must go to tlie forest. No
flower has a more- decided personality-whether its face is
seen peeping from among the dead-leaves, from the base of
some rock, or the brow of some mossy boulder. There are
those who maintain that it has no odor. But really it exhales
a faint, but exquisite, fragrance.
The Hepatica is a near relative of the Wood Anemone. Indeed botanists now call it Anemone Hepatica. Like its delicate
cousin, it is apetalous. Below the calyx, at a -greater or less
distance in particular indi'viduals, is a whorl of three ovate and
soft, silky bracts. Beginners in botany mistake these, and
naturally, for the calyx. The sepals are quite indefinite in
number, as are the stamens and pistils. Its three-lobed, glossy
green leaves add much to its charm, and:theirshape suggestedthe name of Liverwort.
Another early April flower, equally, easy to transplant and to
cultivate, is the pretty Blood-root (Sanguinaria Canadensis). It
belongs to the Poppy family, and its pure white and very deciduous flowers come up enfolded by-a leaf. Later on, this leaf
expands to a great size, and is itself highly ornamental. One
has to be up with the lark to catch its two fugacious sepals.
The Hepatica loves rocky, wooded hillsides, while the Bloodroot seeks the banks of streams. Yet both will thrive under
wholly different surroundings in a city garden. This leads
me to say that many of our wild plants can be cultivated, and
with proper care they will increase in size and beauty. Among
the spring flowers we have tried are Bluets'(Houstonia carulea),
the yellow Violet (Viola pubescens), the wild Columbine (Aquilegia Canadensis), the Indian Turnip (Arisaema tryfphillum),
and the Dutchman's Breeches (Dicentra Cucullaria). All these,
and many more, deserve a place in the flower garden.
Providence, R. I.                Wmn. Whitzman RBlailey.
The Propagation of Magnolias.'N HEN the Magnolias are to be propagated by seed it
should be separated from the pod as soon as ripe,
macerated in water for a week or more, and then, after a
thorough washing in clean water, it should be sown, while still
moist, in pots or boxes filled with light, sandy and well-drained
soil. These should be kept in a cool house until January, when


they may have a temperature of 50~ at night and ioO or I5~
higher during the day. If the soil is kept moist, but not wet, the
seed will usually germinate in five or six weeks, when the young
plants can be removed to small pots or boxes. If shifted on
from small pots to larger ones during the summer, and grown
in a close, moist atmosphere, many of them will be established
and fit to graft by autumn. If not sown in the green-house,
the seed, after being cleaned, should be put in boxes with
sand in alternate layers and placed in a frame or cellar where


MARCH 21, I888.]


Garden and Forest.



</P>
            <P>
               <PB REF="p0012.tif" SEQ="0012" RES="600dpi" FMT="TIFF6.0" FTR="UNSPEC" CNF="878" N="46"/>46


Garden and Forest.


it will not freeze, until about the first of May in this latitude,
when, as soon as the ground becomes warm, it may be
sown out-of-doors. If the seed is not washed clean as soon as
possible after gathering, it quickly becomes rancid, and will
not germinate readily; but when thoroughly cleaned and mixed
with damp sand it will keep for a long time. I have sown the
seed without washing, and the pulp in rotting soured the soil
and a fungus appeared in it, so that the plants had to be moved
into fresh soil to save them.
When the Magnolias are propagated by grafting, the stocks
should be well established in pots the year before and plunged
in a frame or other sheltered place and cared for during the
summer. When cold weather approaches, the pots should be
removed, before they freeze, to a pit or frame where they can
be protected until used. They can be grafted successfully
from the middle of January to the middle of March either by
side or cleft-grafting under double frames-that is, under a
box frame in the green-house. They prefer a slight bottom
heat to start the roots into working condition. The frame
should be kept close for a few days, or weeks, during bright
weather, but air may be given when the house is closed and
on cloudy days. A slight syringing once or twice a day in
bright weather will be beneficial. It is usually from three to
five weeks before grafts can be considered established, although
in from seven fo ten days an estimate can be made of what
percentage has " taken."  Magnolias can also be grafted from
half ripened wood from July to September, and they can be
budded during August or September. They are usually
grafted on stock of M. acuminata and MA. Umbrella; some preferring the latter because of its abundant fibrous roots and the
ease with which it can be transplanted. I prefer, however, A..
acuminata, because the other species suckers, and unless
great care is taken these shoots will kill out the graft in the
young stock.
Magnolias can also be increased by layering; in fact, until
within a few years this was the favorite method of propagation,
and few gardeners knew how to graft themn. -Layering is a
simple operation, and can be performed in spring or summer.
A small trench is dug a little way from the plant, and into this
branches are bent down and held firmly with hooked pegs.
The ends are then turned up, the young branches are tongued
under an eye and the trench is filled up with good loam.
In hot, dry weather, water should be given occasionally. If
layered early some of them will root the first season, although
many of the Magnolias will not root until the second year. As
soon as rooting takes place, the branch should be separated
from the old plant, pruned into shape and transplanted into
good soil in the nursery.
Jamaica Plain, Mass.                 7ackson Dawson.
Rules for Planting Wind-breaks.
THE influence of the wind-break is local and almost entirely
mechanical. It prevents the fierce sweep of winds over
the surface of the ground, and therefore tends to diminish
evaporation from the soil and from plants, especially in cold
weather, and to lessen the mechanical injury to trees and
bush-fruits.  It is apparent to all good observers, however,
that wind-breaks are sometimes injurious. Therefore there
must be certain rules to govern their planting. The most important of these rules, for Michigan especially, may be briefly
stated:
I. The wind-break should not obstruct atmosp5heric drainage.
Cold air is heavier than warm air, and it therefore settles into
the lower areas.  Elevated areas are consequently warmer
than low ones in still weather.  Inasmuch as these high
lands are more wind-swept than others, it has become a common impression that the wind itself is in some manner a protection to fruit plantations, whereas the protection really comes
from atmospheric drainage. The wind-break upon most of
the elevated areas, therefore, should be open enough to allow
of the free drainage of air. In such localities a tight wall of
evergreens is apt to be positively injurious. Deciduous trees,
with perhaps a sparse admixture of evergreens, make the
better wind-breaks for such places. It should be borne in
mind that the object is not to stop the wind, but rather to break
its force, to check it. Breakwaters are often made of a network


of naked spiles rather than a solid wall.
In many interior localities a dense wind-break on the north
and west excites an early growth in tender fruits, thereby
increasing danger from late spring frosts. Hence:
2. The wind-break should never be dense enough to force the
buds on fruit trees, in those localities which  are subject
to late sfiring frosts.  It is evident, therefore, that Spruces


[MARCH 21, I888.


and other evergreens should be planted sparingly in such
places, and that deciduous trees, which do not come early into
leaf, should be chosen.
One of the most disastrous effects of winds in the orchard,
and especially in small fruit plantations, is the sweeping of the
surface of the ground, causing excessive evaporation, carrying
off the snow and thereby exposing the roots and crowns of the
plants to danger. Therefore:
3. As a rule, in localities where atmospheric drainage will
not be seriously checked, the wind-break should have a copfiaratively dense bottomz,fornzed by under6growth or low-branching
trees.
All crops closely adjoining the wind-break suffer from lack
of moisture and food supply, and many small plants, as bushfruits and nursery stock, are broken by the accumulating
snow. Hence:
4. Sofar as practicable, the wind-break should be Slantedat a
distance of six rods or inorefronm thefruitlplantation.
In our severe climate only the most hardy and vigorous
trees should be planted; or, in other words:
5. Native trees and shrubs are preferable for wind-breaks.
Of exotic trees, only the Norway Spruce and Apple are desirble for wind-breaks in Michigan.           L. H. Bailey.
The  Forest.
The Forests of Vancouver Island.
V ANCOUVER ISLAND is situated between the parallels
of 48~ and 5 io N. lat. and b.eteen I 23 0 and i28~ W.
long.  It is about 240 mn.le&lt;-In length and from 40 to
70 in breadth ainl.3 —cofffains about i4,000 square miles.
Witkl,.theexcpiitioll of the southern part and a few settlements at Nanaimo and Comox, the whole island is still
covered by heavy forest.
Through the centre of the island runs a ridge of mountainouis country of varying width, which, commencing
with Donald Peak at Metchosin, runs north-westerly, and,
constantly increasing in altitude, culminates in Mount
Arrowsmith, about Ioo miles from Victoria.  This mountain is 5,976 feet high, but to the north numerous peaks
rise much higher, ranging from 6,00ooo to 8,ooo feet in
height.  Lying between the mountain chains, or at the
base of the single mountains, are numerous lakes of clear
water, which are frequently united by connecting streams
and discharged into the sea by rivers of no great size.
It will thus be seen that but a small portion of the surface of the island is level; indeed, it is for the most part so
elevated that it must be called mountainous rather than
hilly. Owing to the position of the island, in regard to the
Pacific, the low grounds seem to have just as damp an
atmosphere as the more elevated parts, and a wet, cloudy
winter is succeeded by a cloudless, though not atmospherically dry, summer.  These conditions will account
for the remarkable growth of timber on the island and the
appearance of certain trees north of their expected range.
The forest ought, therefore, to be composed chiefly of
mountain species, and this is the fact, as the hardwood
trees of the low or coast districts are of little account in
the general distribution.
The Oak (Quercus Gar;yana) occupies more superficial
area than all the other deciduous trees together.  It is
abundant in all the district around Victoria, seldom growing tall and straight like the eastern Oaks, but appearing
more like the trees in English parks.  Usually the large
trees grow singly amongst the rocks, and their gnarled
trunks and wide spreading limbs appear out of place in
America.  North of Victoria it becomes scarce and at last


ceases to grow at Comox, I40 miles to the north.
Two other trees claim particular notice.  These are the
Madrona (Arbulus Menlz'eszi') and the Flowering Dogwood
(Cornus /Nullaldzi.)  The former, with its large laurel-like
evergreen leaves and reddish bark, would claim attention
anywhere, but to find it a stately forest tree north of the
49th parallel is a remarkable fact. On all the islands in
the Gulf of Georgia, and on all the exposed points of



</P>
            <P>
               <PB REF="p0013.tif" SEQ="0013" RES="600dpi" FMT="TIFF6.0" FTR="UNSPEC" CNF="878" N="47"/>Garden and Forest.


the east coast, it is quite common; but on the gravel which
occurs between the coast and the base of the mountains,
it is frequent, and even on the west coast as far north as
Alberni. Nowhere on the island does the Dog Wood
come to greater perfection than around Nanaimo, and
here, in the middle of May, the borders of the woods
are white with the broad involucres of the cymes of
inconspicuous flowers.  Trees forty feet high are not
uncommon, with trunks from six to twelve inches in
diameter.
By far the finest deciduous leaved tree on the island is
the Broad Leaved Maple (Acer macrophkyllum).  In the
early spring, before the leaves are fully developed, it produces racemes of light yellow  flowers over six inches
long, which are pendant and add much to the beauty of
the tree, as they hang between the young leaves and
give the whole tree a superb appearance.  Later in the
season the broad leaves cover up the fruit and one is
almost tempted to believe that he looks upon a denizen
of the tropics. Bordering ponds and lakelets, and forming thickets so dense that they are almost impenetrable,
are three small trees.  These are the Wild Crab (Pirus
rzvularis), Wild Cherry (Prunus mol/is) and "Barberry"
(Rhamnus Purshiana).   The latter, named "Barberry"
by the settlers, is used medicinally and is widely distributed, being found far to the north.
Poplars, Alders and Willows are of frequent occurrence,
but in no place do they become so abundant as to monopolize much surface.  Small groves of Balsam Poplar
(Populus /rzchocarpa) are found in low spots by the mouths
of rivers, and the trees attain a large size and are tall and
straight, but none of the other species, except one species
of Alder (Alnus rubra), can be considered of value.
The various species of Conifers constitute the true forests of Vancouver Island, and to these we will now turn
our attention. They divide themselves almost insensibly into two groups - one of the coast or lower levels
and the other of the mountains- but some species pass
from  the plain to the mountain, while others are restricted to the coast or to the mountain summit.
The coast species, which are never found on the
mountains, are Abz'es grand/s and Pzcea  ZlMezziesii; together with the Yew (Taxus brev)folha) and the Red Cedar
(Junipnerus Vz-gznimana).  Owing to the peculiar distribution
of the last species, it has been mistaken for the more
southern Junliperus occicdelzahls, but all doubt regarding
it has been removed the past summer. On the shores of
Cameron and Horne lakes, near the centre of the island,
fine trees line the shore and overhang the water, but
they are never seen in the forest.  The Yew is not uncommon in many places near Victoria, but it is sparingly
distributed and seldom a marked feature of the forest
growths.
The Fir (Ab/es grandis) is a noble tree and is a most
striking object in the river valleys near the coast on both
sides of the island. In company with the Sitka Spruce it
forms many beautiful groves in the low country between
Nanaimo and Comox. Beyond the latter point the Spruce
becomes a more characteristic feature and even rivals the
stately Douglas Fir itself.  Around Alberni and in the
valleys of the Somas River and the lakes connected with
it these trees attain very great dimensions and often tower
up 200 feet, with a beautiful pyramidal head of short,
light green branches.
Pinus contor/a is either represented by tree forms or has
a most peculiar habit. At one time it is found clinging
to the rocks close to the sea, at another growing in a bog
in company with KCalmia and Ledum, and at Qualicllm
it forms a strip of forest nearly five miles wide that inter

venes between the sea and the base of the mountains.
Here the soil is chiefly gravel, and the tree looks very
much like its cousin of the Rocky Mountains, Piizus M2Irrayana, and certainly grows under the same conditions,
except that of altitude.
Ottawa, Canada.  aohn IMacoun.


47


Propagation of Conifers from Seeds in the
Open Air.
UNTIL about thirty-five years ago no one had succeeded
in growing Conifers from seed in America, except under
glass. Consequently our American nurseries were stocked with
imported seedlings of the foreign kinds and with native seedlings collected in the forests.
I had seen large quantities grown in the full sunlight in the
North of England as easily as Carrots and with no shelter, and
therefore began by investing $70 in seeds of the common European kinds and in several hundredweight of seeds of the native kinds collected for me in the Green Mountains. I sowed
them on four acres; they germinated finely, and were a beautiful sight; -'I had about a week of unalloyed pleasure, except
for an hour now and then consumed in wondering where
a market could be found for such a large amount of stock.
This problem, however, was soon solved.  A bright day,
a gathering thunder-shower, a heavy rain and the sudden
reappearance of the scorching sun at about 2 P. M.! I went to
examine my seedlings, and found them all down flat, damped
off or scorched off, except a part of those latest in starting
that were just breaking ground. I immediately sent for 4,000
feet of lumber, and this, with the help of an adjoining rail fence,
was soon worked up int6 a shelter; but at the end of the season not one seedling was left.
I should gladly have given up and made no further experiments, but I had announced that success was coming, and it
was too late to retreat. So I took to the woods and studied
the surroundings of the seedlings in the forests. It was plain
that Nature had a decided advantage over me, as it cost her
nothing for seeds, and she apparently did not raise more than
one or two trees from a million of them. Finally, after the
next winter was nearly over, and I had secured a large stock of
seed for spring sowing, I bethought me of several hundred
gunny bags that had lain for years unclaimed in a steamboat
warehouse. Securing them, we sowed our seed in four-feet
beds, stretched the gunny bags tightly on the frames one foot
from the ground, and succeeded in raising a fair crop, as tile
bags let the rain through evenly.
It was soon evident that the more open the sacking was, the
less the plants damped off, showing that they required more sunlight. We then built frames of lath, leaving spaces between.
Experiments were made to ascertain the degree of sunlight
most favorable to the seedlings, and it was found that we succeeded best when one-inch spaces were left between the
laths, with the frames they rested on six inches high. We followed this lath-shading   for several years, until we found it
almost impossible to get the quantity of lath we needed, as at
the lumber mills they were only prepared to sell a certain proportion of lath with a cargo of lumber.
Finally, over twenty years ago, we adopted our present
mode of shading with posts, poles and brush. Not that we
considered it cheaper or better than the lath screens, btut the
material can be more readily obtained. Rows of posts seven
feet high are set ten feet apart and eight feet distant in the
rows. Fence-boards six or eight inches wide and sixteen feet
long are nailed upon these at the top. Slender poles are laid
across, and on these are placed branches of trees with the
leaves on them. The beds are four feet wide and are laid out so
that the row of posts runs up the middle of each alternate bed.
If the soil is tenacious we throw it up in ridges the previous
fall. The beds are raked very fine, the seeds sown dry in
springt, broadcast, and raked in-the fine seeds lightly, the larger
seeds more deeply. We cannot protect the seeds from birds
with the brush shade as conveniently as with lath screens, but
must cover them with brush or straw, or they Mwill be scratched
out.
The seeds are souwn thickly, the European Larch more
thickly than the others, as the imperfect seeds cannot be separated, for they are merchantable when one-third to one-half
are " blind " seeds. From the time the seedlings appear above
ground until they begin their second growth, they are liable to
"damp off" during murky weather, ill which case the screens
must be taken off; but great care must be taken to have them


replaced without loss of time when the sun appears. We
formerly used dry sand, sprinkled over the beds, to check the
damping off, but could perceive little or no benefit from it.
"Rich soil encourages damping off."  The beds must be
thoroughly hand-weeded during the summer. Late in autumn
the beds should be covered with forest leaves, with a light
covering of straw or brush to prevent their being blown off.
Larches are usually thinned out of the beds at one year old;
other Conifers at two years old.         Robert Douglas.


MARCI  21I, 1888.]



</P>
            <P>
               <PB REF="p0014.tif" SEQ="0014" RES="600dpi" FMT="TIFF6.0" FTR="UNSPEC" CNF="881" N="48"/>48                                            Garden ai
Recent Publications.
Review of Forest Administration in British India for the
year z88j-86, by B. Ribbentrop,Acting Inspector-General, Indian
Forest Department. Simla, I887. Report of the Forest Dejartmnent, Madras Presidency, for the year I885-86, by Lt.-Col. I.
CambeldWalker. Madras, I887.
These two Reports have only just reached us. They contain the record of the work done in the Indian forests, with its
financial results, for the period which they cover. The Indian
Forest Department is less than a quarter of a century old.
Its organization by Dr. Brandis in the face of serious native
opposition, great natural difficulties, and without, at the start,
a properly trained staff of assistants, is one of the greatest administrative triumphs of recent times.
The Indian forests, previous to the establishment of the
Forest Department, yielded nothing to the Government. In the
years covered by these Reports the net profit derived from
working them systematically was over three and one-half
million dollars, the operating expenses amounting to sixtythree per cent. of the gross revenue. The net receipts of the
Department have increased steadily for a number of years;
and they will, it seems pretty safe to predict, continue to
increase as long as it is administered in the same able
manner.
The history of forest administration in India might be
studied with advantage by the Secretary of the Interior and
members of Congress of the United States. The forests which
grow upon our national domain produce no income. The
land upon which they stand is sold sometimes at a mere nominal price, and while the Government is waiting for customers
the forests themselves are robbed of their best timber, burned,
pastured, devastated and destroyed.
Recent Plant Portraits.
Botanical Magazine, January, Phormiuzm Hookeri, t. 6973; a
third species of the New Zealand Flax; discovered several
years ago on the Waitangi River "growing pendulous from
almost perpendicular rocks, in great abundance"; and now
cultivated in southern England, where it flowers and ripens its
seed very freely.
Ceratothica triloba, 1. 6974; a tall pubescent herb with the
habit of a Foxglove, native of Natal and closely allied to the
common cultivated Indian Sesamnzn Indicu;m, L.
Thunbergia affinis, t. 6975; a tall shrub, a. native of Zanzibar,
with handsome dark blue flowers, similar, although far more
beautiful, than those of the old T. erecta.
Prunus 7acquezionlii, t. 6976; a dwarf, compact, hardy
shrub, with delicate pink flowers; conmmon in the northwestern Himnalayas acnd extending into Thibet and Afghanistan.
J/Iasdevallia Chestertonzi, i. 6977; a rather sinall flowered, and,
horticulturally, not very attractive species of this ininiense
genus; a native of New Grenada.
Periodical Literature.
T  HE Art Azalteur for January, I888, contains a pleasant and
suggestive paper on Japanese modes of arranging cut
flowers, leaves and branches. The matter is one which the
Japanese only have considered from an artistic point of view,
but which certainly ought to be so considered by all who profess to care for flowers or for beauty in the abstract. Therefore this article is welcome, although it gives but a hint of the
great stress which the educational systems of Japan lay upon
the art of floral arrangement, and explains, with the aid of illustrations, only one or two of the effects they consider desirable, and one or two of the skillful and ingenious devices in
which the student is instructed.
Cassell's Fanzily Magazine will print during the year a series
of popular articles treating of the garden and the work to be
done in it during each successive month. ("The Garden in


January" and "The Garden in February" have already appeared; and while they naturally have a greater practical value
for the English than for the American reader, they are by no
means devoid of interest even for the latter.
Longinaz s MIagazine for February, I888, contains a brightly
written chapter on "-Orchids," by Frederick Boyle, a man of
letters by profession, but an enthusiastic, and, from his own
account, a successful horticulturist in his leisure hours. It is
accompanied by none of the charming illustrations which
have been given with articles on the same subject in more


n1


d  Porest.                                     [MARCH 21, I888.
than one of our own popular magazines, and its'purpose is not,
like theirs, descriptive. Its purpose is simply to prove to those
who are already well aware of the beauty of Orchids, that it is
by no means so difficuult a task as amateurs generally suppose, to grow many species to perfection by the aid of the simplest arrangements and with the expenditure of very little time
or pains.
IN McMillan's Magazine for January, I888, Forestry is discussed by Mr. George Cadell, formerly connected with the Indian Forestry Department. Some time ago the House of
Commons for the third time appointed a Commission to inquire "Whether by the establishment of a forest school, or
otherwise, our waste lands could be made more remunerative." At the time when Mr. Cadell wrote, this Commission
had reported to Parliament, but no action had yet been taken
on its report. Meanwhile he discusses the condition of the
Crown forests in England, briefly explains the management of
those in India, refers to the great benefitswhich France and
Switzerland have received from a judicious system of control,
and points out as a subject for national mortification that both
at the Cape and in Cyprus, England has been obliged to depend
upon the services of foreign experts in Forestry.
Flower Market.
NEW YORK, March w6th, r888.
The quality of cut flowers is much better this week than last, notwithstanding a large quantity has been held on snow-bound trains.
Hybrid Roses are very handsome, but have declined somewhat, those
selected of favorite sorts bringing only 6o to 75 cts. each. There was
no demand for flowers during the storm of the early week, but trade
has been picking up since and is brisk to-day. There is an over supply of La France Roses, the very choicest bringing but $2.50 a dozen.
The finest Puritans sell for 50 cts. Ulrich Brunner sells rapidly at 75
cts. a flower.  Popular varieties of Tea Roses, such as Papa Gontier,
bring $I.oo a dozen.  Selected buds of Bride or Cornelia Cook cost
$3.00 a dozen. Tulips, Lilies-of-the-Valley and Roman Hyacinths are
75 cts. a dozen.  Dutch Hyacinths are in large variety and in lively
demand at 15 cts. a spike; Mignonette from 50 cts. to $1.50 a dozen
spikes; Carnations from 35 cts. to 50 cts. a dozen, the latter price
being for favorite kinds, such as Buttercup and Grace Wilder. Violets
continue firm at $I.oo a hundred for the average quality and $1.50
for those of extra beauty and fragrance.  Smilax costs 30 cts. a yard.
PHILADELPHIA, Mfarch I6tZh.
The severe snow storm prevented growers from shipping floxvers to
the city in the early part of the week. Italso interfered with the
demand and prices have varied little since last quotations. The most
notable Rose now inl market is Madarne Gabriel Luizet. Finer flowers of
this variety were never before seen here; they are selling from 75 cts.
to $1.5oeach. Mrs. John Laing is also cut in quantity; the latter is
the newer, but it can never displace Madame Luizet, excepting, perhaps, for very early work. Puritans are improving in quality, and
are in fair demand; it is not a first-class Rose to ship long distances;
some of the growers bring it to the city in deep boxes of moss, into
which the stems are thrust; this holds them steady and upright and insures safe arrival. Heath is in fair demand at 15 cts. per spray. The
kind offered is a variety of Erica caffra alba, and is grown near Boston.
It is rarely used alone, but is added to boxes of choice flowers, or is
arranged with Orchids.
BOSTON, March 6ith.
There is little change in the cut-flower market. Hybrid Roses and
Jacqueminots are if anything more abundant and of still better quality.
Both yellow and white Roses are scarce and they are eagerly taken as
fast as brought to the city by the growers.  Tulips, Lilies-of-theValley, and other bulbous flowers are still plentiful. Roman Hyacinths
are scarce, but in their stead there is an abundance of the Italian
variety, which, although slightly pinkish in color, has the advantage of
bearing a larger and stronger flower spike than does the Roman. The
supply of Carnations is diminishing, and prices will undoubtedly
advance considerably before Easter. A few White Lilies are seen, but


they are mostly short stemmed and are of little use excepting for
funeral designs. Harris's Lilies and Callas are worth $3.o0 per dozein.
Most people in buying Callas now require a few of the leaves with the
flowers, which add much to their appearance. Hybrid Roses of extra
quality bring from $6 to $9 per dozen. Jacqueminots, Mermets and a fair
quality of hybrids are $3.00; Perles, Niphetos and Bon Silene, $I per
dozen; Lilies-of-the-Valley, Tulips and Narcissus of various kinds average about $I.oo per dozen. French Marguerites, Mignonette, Forget-menots, Carnations and Heliotrope sell for about 50 cts. per dozen sprays;
Pansies and Violets 50 cts. per bunch. Among Orchids the most attractive now in season are the Odontoglossums. Nothing more beautiful
for a bridal wreath or coronet than a spray of 0. Alexandra.
Perfect sprays are worth from $2.00 to $3.00 each.


I    ir-             I



</P>
            <P>
               <PB REF="p0015.tif" SEQ="0015" RES="600dpi" FMT="TIFF6.0" FTR="ADV" CNF="854" N="iii"/>XMARCH 21, I888.]                                       Garden  and   Forest.                                                                iii
GARDEN AND FOREST:
An Illustrated Weekly Journal of Horticulture, Landscape Art and Forestry,
GARDEN AND FOREST will be devoted to Horticulture in all its branches, Garden Botany, Dendrology and Landscape Gardening,;lad will discuss Plant Diseases and Insects injurious to vegetation.
Professor C. S. SARGENT, of Harvard College, will have general editorial control of GARDEN AND FOREST.
Professor WM. G. FARLOW, of Harvard College, will have editorial charge of the Department of Cryptogamic Botany and Plant
Diseases.
Professor A. S. PACKARD, of Brown University, will have editorial charge of the Department of Entomology.
Mr. WM. A. STILES will be the Managing Editor.
GARDEN AND FOREST will record all noteworthy discoveries and all progress in science and practice within its field at home:and abroad. It will place scientific information clearly and simply before the public, and make available for the instruction of all
persons interested in garden plants the conclusions reached by the most trustworthy  investigators.  Arrangements have been made to
figure and describe new and little-known plants (especially North American) of horticultural promise. A department will be devoted to
the history and description of ornamental trees and shrubs.  New  florists' flowers, fruits and vegetables will be made known, and
-experienced gardeners will describe practical methods of cultivation.
GARDEN AND FOREST will report the proceedings of the principal Horticultural Societies of the United States and the.condition of the horticultural trade in the chief commercial centres of the country.
GARDEN AND FOREST, in view of the growing taste for rural life, and of the multiplication of country residences in all
lparts of the United States, especially in the vicinity of the cities and of the larger towns, will make a special feature of discussing the
planning  and  planting  of private  gardens and  grounds,  small and  large, and  will endeavor to  assist all who desire to make
their home  surroundings attractive  and  artistic.   It will be a medium  of  instruction  for all persons interested in  preserving:and developing the beauty of natural scenery.  It will co-operate with Village Improvement Societies and every  other organized
-effort to secure  the  proper ordering and  maintenance of parks and  squares, cemeteries, railroad  stations, school- grounds  and
roadsides.  It will treat of Landscape Gardening in all its phases; reviewing its history and discussing its connection with architecture.
GARDEN  AND  FOREST  will give special attention to scientific and practical Forestry in their various departments, including
-Forest Conservation and economic Tree Planting, and to all the important questions which grow out of the intimate relation of the
forests of the country to its climate, soil, water supply and material development.
Original information on all these subjects will be furnished by numerous American and foreign correspondents.
Among those who have promised contributions to GARDEN AND FOREST are:
IMr. SERENO WATSON, Curator of the Herbarium, Har- Mr. FREDERICK LAW OLMSTED, Brookline, Mass.   Dr. KARL MOHR, Mobile, Ala.
vard College.             "                  FRANCIS PARKMAN, Boston.                     Hon. J. B. WALKER, Forest Commissioner of New
-Prof. GEO. L. GOODALE, Harvard College.         Dr. C. C. PARRY, San Francisco.                        Hampshire.
4; WOLCOTT GIBBS,        "                    Mr. PROSPERJ. BERCKMANS, President of the American Mr. WM. HAMILTON GIBSON, Brooklyn, N. VY.
" W.M. H. BREWER, Yale College.                      Pomological Society.                         EDGAR 1. ENSIGN, Forest Commissioner of ColeD. G. EATON,                 "              " CHARLES A. DANA, New York.                          rado.
WWM. J. BEAL, Agricultural College of Michigan.   " BURNET LANDRETH, Philadelphia.          " E. S. CARMAN, Editor of the Rural Nlew Yor/eer.
L. H. BAILEY, TR.,'.    C        " ROBERT RIDGEWAY, Washington, D. C.' WMn. M. CANBY, Wilmington, Del.
J. L. BUDD, Agricultural College of Iowa.         CALVERT VAUX, New York.                       " JOHN ROBINSON, Salemn, Mass.
B. D. HALSTED,  "'     {X       49         {' J. B. HARRISON, Franklin Falls, N. H.            J. D. LYMAN, Exeter, N. H.
E. W. HILGARD,Universily of California.       Dr. HENRY P WALCOTT, President of the Massachusetts  " SAMUEL PARSONS, JR., Superintendent of Central
J. T. ROTHROCK, University of Pennsylvania.       Horticultural Society.                          Park, N. Y.
"  CHAS. E. BESSEY, University of Nebraska.   Mr. C. G. PRINGLE, Charlotte, Vt.                 " WM. MCMILLAN, Superintendent of Parks, Buffalo,
WMn. TRELEASE, Shaw School of Botany, St. Louis.  " ROBERT DOUGLAS, Waukegan, III.               N. Y.'  T. J. BURRILL, University of Illinois.         H. W. S. CLEVELAND, Minneapolis, Minn.        "SYLVESTER BAXTER, Boston.
W. W. BAILEY, Brown University.  CHAS. W. GARFIELD, Secretary of the American  " CHARLES ELIOT, Boston.
E. A. POPENOE, Agricultural College, Kansas.      Pomological Society.                      "JOHN THORPE, Secretary of the New York HortiRAPHAEL PUMPELLY, United States Geological " C. R. ORCUTT, San Diego, Cal.                        cultural Society.
Survey.                                      B. E. FERNOW, Chief of the Forestry Division, Wash-  " EDWIN LONSDALE, Secretary of the Philadelphia
CJAMES H. GARDINER, Director New York State      ington, D. C.                                    Horticultural Society.
Survey.                                   " JOHNBIRKENBINE, Secretary of the Pennsylvania    ROBERT CRAIG, President of the Philadelphia' Win. R. LAZENBY, Director of the Ohio Agricul-     Forestry Association.                           Florists' Club.
tural Experiment Station.                 "JOSIAH HOOPES, West Chester, Pa.               " SAMUEL B. PARSONS, Flushing, N. Y.
"  W. W. TRACY, Detroit, Mich.                 " PETER HENDERSON, New York.                     " GEORGE ELLWANGER, Rochester.
"  C. V. RILEY, Washington, D. C.' WM. FALCONER, Glen Cove, N. Y.                 " P. H. BARRY, Rochester.
Mr. DONALD G. MITCHELL, New Haven, Conn.         "JACKSON DAWSON, Jamaica Plain, Mass.              W. J. STEWART, Boston, Mass.
"' FRANKJ. ScorT, Toledo, O.                    " WM. H. HALL, State Engineer, Sacramento, Cal.    W. A. MANDA, Botanic Gardens, Cambridge,
Hon. ADOLPHE LEU~, Secretary of the Ohio Forestry   C. C. CROZIER, Department of Agriculture, Wash-    Mass.
Bureau.                                        in fton, D. C.                                DAVID ALLAN, Mount Vernon, Mass.' B. G. NORTHROP, Clinton, Conn.              The Rev. _. P. RoE, Cornwall, N. Y.              " WM. ROBINSON, North Easton, Mass.
Mr. G. W. HOTCHKISS, Secretary of the Lumber Manu- Dr. C. C. ABBO TT, Trenton, N. J.                A. H. FEWKES, Newton Highlands, Mass.
facturers' Association.                  Mrs. SCHUYLER VAN RENSSELAER, New York.             F. GOLDRING, Kenwood, N. Y.
Dr. C. L. ANDERSON, Santa Cruz, Cal.              " MARY TREAT, Vineland, N.J.                   " C. M. ATKINSON, Brookline, Mass.


Dr. MAXWELL T. MASTERS, Editor of the Gardener's M. EDOUARD ANDRE, Editor of the Revue Horticole, Paris, M. J. ALLARD, Angers, Maine &amp; Loire, France.
ChronTice.                                       France.                                    Dr. H. MAYR, University of Tokio, Japan.
Mr. GEO. NICHOLSON, Curator of the Royal Gardeis, Dr. G. M. DAWSON, Geological Survey of Canada.    Prof. D. P. Penhallow, Director of the Botanical GarKew.                                      Prof. JOHN MACOUN,   X;'                           dens, Montreal.
X W. B. HEMSLEY, Herbarium, Royal Gardens, Kew. M. CHARLES NAUDIN, Director of the Gardens of the Mr. WM. SAUNDERS, Director of the AgriculturalExperiWM. GOLDRING, London.                                Villa Thuret, Antibes.                            ment Station, Ontario.
"MNr. MAX LEICIHTLIN, Baden Baden.                Dr. CHAS. BOLLE, Berlin.                           " WIn. LITTLE, Montreal.
Single numbers, IO  cents.  Subscription  price, Four Dollars a year, in  advance.
THE GARDEN AND FOREST PUBLISHING CO., Limited,
TRIBUNE BUILDING, NEW YORK.
-D. A. MUNRO, MNana- e.



</P>
            <P>
               <PB REF="p0016.tif" SEQ="0016" RES="600dpi" FMT="TIFF6.0" FTR="ADV" CNF="832" N="iv"/>iv


Seeds, Seeds, Seeds.
To our friends who have not
already received it, we are ready
to mail our
NEW CATALOGUE


OF
HIGH CLASS SEEDS
FOR 1888,
Containing all the Novelties of
the Season, both in VEGETABLE,
FLOWER and TREE Seeds.
J. M.Thorburn &amp; Co.,
15 JOHN STREET,
NEW YORK.


Garden and Forest.


Now offeredfo rELLWANG ER A valuable new
the first time.  &amp;-BARRY,     Grape.
THE MILLS GRAPE
Circular wsth   MT. HOPE   andsorne an
fu lp aric   ular URSERIES   of fi ne
by mail free.  ochester.Y  Qu ality,


SPRING PLANTINC.
BREES   We offr the largest and most com.
plete general stock in the U. S., be.
Fruit &amp; Ornamental. sides many Novelties.Catalogues
sent to all regular customers,free.
To others: No. 1, Fruits, 10c.; No. 2,
Ornamental Trees, etc., illustrated,
15c.; No. 3, Strawberries; No. 4,
GRAPE VINES Wholesale; No. 5. Roses. Free.
GRAPE VINES ELLWANGER &amp; BARRY
MT. HOPE NIRSERIESS ROCHESTER,New York.


IBLEY'S TESTED SEED
Catalogue free on application.
Send for it.
HIRA I SIBLEY &amp; CO.,
ROCHESTER, N. Y., &amp; CHICAGO, ILL.


For successful Gardening, try
-I.'


VEGETABLE  SEEDS.   The best and most
popular sorts in England.
FLOWER  SEEDS, The greatest variety offered
by any house.
gi-Descriptive Seed List free on application.
Seeds and Bulbs shipped to all parts of the world.


DIIN   noi-Itif"wovz  3 53                   e es0g


1838 POMONA  NUIRSIIES  1888
Parry, Lida and Bomba Strawberries, Marlboro and
Golden Queen Raspberries, Wilson Jr., Erie and
Minnewaski Blackberries, Niagara, Empire State
and Moore's Early Grapes, Lawson, Kieffer and
LeConte Pears, Wonderful and Globe Peach, Spaulding and Japan Plums, Delaware Winter and Red
Cider Apples. All the worthy old and promising
new varieties. Catalogue Free.
WM. PARRY, PARRY, N. J.


[MARCH  21, 1888.


J LAING &amp; SONS,
The Nurseries,
FOREST HILL, LONDON,,
ENGLAND.
LEADING SPECIALTIES.
TUBEROUS *BEGONIAS.
AWARDED FOUR GOLD MEDALS..Gold Medal Collection, quite unrivaled.' Tubers ina'dry state can be safely transmitted from England~
until April.
PRICES WHEN SELECTION IS LEFT TO US:
Per DozA Collection, Named, our best collection.......... 42s.


B
C
D
1
P
G
H
J
K
L
m


~ " very choice selection.... 36schoice selection......... 30s"        \very good selection.....24s."c good selection.......... 8ss"'      ordinary selection......I2s.
Unnamed    best selections to color.. 2zS.
very choice selection... i8s.
(" best whites, distinct.....I5s(" choice selection......... I2s.
very good, selected to
color for bedding.. gs...
("       good best do.per xoo, 40S., 6s.
DOUBLE VARIETIES.'


OUR
No== 


EVERYTHINO OARDEN
is this season the grandest ever issued,
containing three colored plates and
superb illustrations of everything that is
new, useful and rare in Seeds and
Plants, t6gether with plain directions
of "How to grow them," by PETER HENDERsoN. This Manual, which is a book
of 140 pages, we mail to any address on
receipt of 25 cents (in stamps.) To all so
remitting 25 cents for the Manual, we will,
at the same time, send free by mail, in
addition, their choice of any one of the
following novelties, the price of either of
-  which is 25 cents: One packet of the new
Green and Gold Watermelon, or one
packet of new Succession Cabbage, or
one packet of new Zebra Zinnia, or one
packet of Butterfly Pansy (see illustration_) or onen nacket of new lamnmoth


GOLD MEDAL, PARIS, 1878.
BAKER'S
Breakfast Cocoa.
Warrarn ed absolutely pure
Cocoa, from which the excess of
Oil has been removed. It has three
times the strength of Cocoa mixed
with Starch, Arrowroot or Sugar,
and is therefore far more economical, costing less than one cent a
cup. It is delicious, nourishing,
strengthening, eas'i. igested, and
admirably adapted for invalids as
well-a, for persons in health.
SoId by Grocers everywhere.
W, BAKER  &amp;  CO, Dorchester, Mass.


yard. Also all kinds of Waterproof Covers for Trucks, Wagons,
Agr. imp'ments, Hay Stacks and all farmers' purposes. Cheap, strong,
durable. Circulars and I U. S. Waterproofing Fibre Co.,
samples free by mail.            nG South Street, New York.


[EPRICES (OUR SELECTION):
P Collection, Named, our best collection, each
7s. 6d. and Ios. 6d.Per Doz.
R " I                    very choice ditto........63s.
S      4     " " choice ditto.............48s.
T      ". very good ditto.........42s.W           Unnamed   our very choice, selected,
distinct............30s.
X                        choice, selected in 6 colors................ 24S.
Z.           mixed ditto............. 8s
BEGONIA SEED.
Gold Medal strain from Prize Plants. New Crop..
Sealed packets. Choice mixed, from single varieties,
Is. and 2s. 6d. per packet; 5s. and Ios. extra large
packets; double varieties, IS., 2S. 6d. and 5s. perpacket; large packets, Ios. Collections-I2 named varieties, single, separate, 5s. 6d.; 6 named varieties,.
separate, 3S.
CALADIUM ROOTS.
The Finest Collection in the world. Best named:,
varieties, per doz., 30os., 36s., 42s., 48s. and 6os.
GLOXINIA ROOTS.
In dormant state till March. Our unequalled collection.
Self colors, and spotted. Best sorts to name, r2s., X8s.,.
24s., 30S., 36s. and 42S. per doz. Unnamed, very choice,.
6s., 9s. and I2s. per doz.
GLOXINIA SEED.
Saved from our Prize Plants; erect flowering, droop —
ing, mixed'and spotted, separate, per packet, IS., 2S..
6d. and 5s.
OTHER FLOWER SEEDS.
The choicest strains of Primula, Cineraria, Calceo —
laria, Cyclamen, Hollyhock, Dahlia, Pansies, Asters,
Stocks, and every other sort.
All kinds of Plants, Roses, Fruit Trees, etc., that can;
be imported from England, safely transmitted in Wardian cases.
A  Remittances or London References must always
accompany orders. Flower Seeds by post. Ordersshould reach us soon as possible.
Jo- CATALOGUES GRATIS AND POST FREE. A..


M


ROCHESTER                               NEWR
CO M MERCII                          DRand
NURSERIESi                   RELIABLE
Address                     oth Fruit and Ornamental. ROSES,Yines,
uW.S.LITTLE                  lematsRhododedron'we e To1is. Catalogue
Rochester,                6 cts. Free to customers.
N.Y.                    0i0 Wholesale LIst, FRIEE.


I 



</P>
         </DIV1>
      </BODY>
   </TEXT>
</DLPSTEXTCLASS>